I'll send you guys some information on Wednesday,
我会在周三发布一些信息给你们，
so if you free come down,
所以如果你有空的话，
gonna be 11 to 1, at night.
晚上 11 点到 1 点，
Okay, and you, you said you have a bouncer,
好的，你说你有一个保镖，
that's gonna ignore the IDs or you have like fake IDs,
他会忽略身份证，或者你有假身份证，
that you're going to hand out on the side as a business,
你会把它当做生意来分发，
and all of that information I cannot say in this class.
所有这些信息我都不能在课上说出来。
Okay, please don't do that, please don't do that.
好的，请不要那样做，请不要那样做。
Okay, great, excellent,
好的，很好，
and we'll have a trip report for some of you guys make it to that,
我们会为你们中的一些人准备一份旅行报告，
so.
所以。
Alright, sorry about taking a little bit of time to get started,
好的，很抱歉花了一点时间才开始，
I had a bunch of people at the office hours,
我在办公时间有一大群人，
but we're going to talk about the concurrency control today.
但我们今天要讨论的是并发控制。
And let's just jump right into it.
让我们直截了当地开始吧。
Alright, so let's get into this.
好的，让我们开始这个。
You've seen this diagram of what a database engine looks like,
你已经看到了数据库引擎的示意图，
as a modular architecture for the different components.
作为不同组件的模块化体系结构。
We are going to talk today about concurrency control mechanisms,
今天我们将讨论并发控制机制，
that hit across these different layers,
影响这些不同层，
which largely hits the operator execution and the access method layers.
这在很大程度上影响到操作执行层和访问方法层。
In two classes from now,
从现在开始的两节课中，
we'll talk about recovery methods,
我们将讨论恢复方法，
which is at the buffer pool and disk manager layers.
这在缓冲池层和磁盘管理器层。
Now all of this will become a lot more clear,
现在，所有这些都将变得更加清晰，
as we jump into what that transaction management mean,
随着我们深入了解事务管理的含义，
what does recovery mean.
恢复的含义。
So let's go straight to that.
所以让我们直接开始吧。
So transaction management allows us to do things safely in a database system,
所以，事务管理允许我们在数据库系统中安全地做事情，
in situations where multiple things are getting updated all at the same time.
在同时更新多个东西的情况下。
Let's start with a simple example.
让我们从一个简单的例子开始。
Here is a schematic of database operations,
这是一个数据库操作的示意图，
These could be fired through a SQL query,
这些可以通过一个 SQL 查询来触发，
from the perspective of the transaction management component,
从事务管理组件的角度来看，
we are largely going to look at the operations that happen at the object level.
我们将在很大程度上查看对象级别发生的操作。
So imagine we fired up a transaction
想象一下，我们启动了一个事务，
and that ends up reading an object,
它最终读取一个对象，
could be a record, could be a page,
可能是一个记录，也可能是一个页面，
we're just going to refer to them as objects here in this class,
在这节课中，我们只将它们称为对象，
does some checking of that value,
对该值进行一些检查，
does some action like pay
执行一些操作，比如支付，
and then updates that A by subtracting 25 from it
然后通过从 A 中减去 25 来更新它，
and eventually writes that,
最终将其写入，
for the purpose of the discussion for transaction management,
为了讨论事务管理，
we are largely concerned with the read and write operations,
我们主要关注读写操作，
that happen with each of these database objects,
这些数据库对象中所发生的，
you can think of them as records, pages, tables, what have you,
你可以把它们想象成记录、页面、表等，
it won't matter,
这无关紧要，
just assume the read and writes for objects that are in the database is what we care about.
只是假设我们关心的是数据库中对象的读取和写入。
And we want to have certain properties about these read and write,
我们希望有关于这些读写的某些属性。
to ensure notions of correctness as we define it,
来确保我们定义的正确性概念，
and that's what transaction management does.
这就是事务管理所做的。
So what could go wrong,
那么，可能会出什么问题，
this is a simple set of actions,
这是一组简单的操作，
that are presented to the database
它们被呈现给数据库，
in response to a query that an application might have sent,
以响应应用程序可能发送的查询，
and a couple things could go wrong.
可能出现的几个错误。
So here on the right side,
所以在右边，
you see the bank balance starts out, has a value of 100,
你可以看到银行余额开始的值为 100 ，
the first thing that happens is does that check
发生的第一件事是检查，
and everything looks okay,
一切看起来是正常的，
it says yes, that check passes,
它说是的，那个检查通过了，
so there's sufficient balance to pay 25 dollars,
所以有足够的余额来支付 25 美元，
so this is you going to an ATM asking for a withdrawal,
所以这是你去自动取款机要求取款，
and pays you that 25 dollars,
然后付给你 25 美元，
so you now have it
这样你就有了它，
and the new balance is calculated,
新的余额计算出来，
and that balance now gets written to your bank account.
现在，这些余额会记入你的银行账户。
Okay, so after the new balance gets calculated,
好的，在计算出新的余额后，
that last action of bank balance of 75
银行余额为 75 的最后一个操作，
is that write operation, that you see in that code on the left side.
是你在左侧代码中看到的写入操作。
But now, what if,
但是现在，如果，
after the ATM machine spitted out the 25 dollars,
在 ATM 机吐出25美元后，
you went and yanked that ATM machine power cord,
你去拉了 ATM 机的电源线，
so that it could not send the write back,
这样它就不能把写入发回了，
okay, imagine you were that fast,
好的，想象一下你那么快，
or there's a natural power failure,
或者是自然停电了，
so the paying action,
所以支付操作，
and the write to the database is not atomic,
和对数据库的写入不是原子的，
they're happening in different systems,
它们发生在不同的系统中，
they might even be geographically spread across,
它们甚至可能在地理上分布得很广，
and bad things could happen in between those actions.
在这些行动之间，可能会发生糟糕的事情。
So how do we make sure that this transaction is correct,
那么，我们如何确保这笔交易是正确的，
obviously, we don't want that,
显然，我们不希望这样，
Your bank would be very upset,
你的银行会非常不安，
if that's how database systems work,
如果数据库系统是这样工作的，
because they would be losing money, if this happens.
因为如果发生这个，他们会赔钱。
So we want this type of stuff to be protected
那么我们希望这种类型的东西受到保护，
and we'll talk about how.
我们将讨论如何保护。
Here's another scenario,
这是另一个场景，
a different scenario,
一个不同的场景，
showing a different type of problems that we also need to worry about.
展示了一个我们也需要担心的不同类型的问题。
So this is not a power failure or things of that sort,
所以，这不是停电或诸如此类的事情，
but concurrent actions.
而是同时发生的行动。
So imagine,
所以想象一下，
you and your significant other both shared this bank account
你和你的另一半都共享这个银行账户，
and you have individual debit cards,
你有个人借记卡，
that allow you to debit from that same bank account,
允许你从同一个银行账户借记，
and you both go to two separate ATMs
你们两个去两个不同的 ATM 机，
and simultaneously run this transaction,
同时执行这笔交易，
so both of you are running these sequence of actions to withdraw 25 dollars,
你们两个都在运行取款 25 美元的操作序列，
and, sufficient balance is checked on both sides,
余额足够在两边检查通过，
you get paid, ATM spits out 25 dollars,
你得到付款， ATM 吐出了 25 美元，
your significant other gets paid,
你的另一半也得到了付款，
but now, because both of them read the original bank balance,
但是现在，因为他们两人都读取了原始的银行余额，
both of them have calculated the new balance as being 75,
他们都计算出了新的余额为 75 ，
because everything looks correct,
因为一切看起来都是对的，
and then the first one writes,
然后第一个写入，
the second one overwrites that,
第二个覆盖了它，
and now the bank is short 25 dollars.
现在银行缺少了 25 美元。
Again, this is not, ideal situation for the banks,
再说一次，对银行来说，这不是一个理想的局面，
banks would never use database systems,
银行永远不会使用数据库系统，
or enterprises wouldn't use database systems,
或者企业不会使用数据库系统，
if these types of things are allowed to happen.
如果允许这种事情发生。
So semantically,
所以，在语义上，
what we wanted is that,
我们希望的是，
we wanted the database,
我们希望数据库，
application was sending this read and write request,
发送这个读写请求的应用，
that was written by some application code,
由一些应用程序代码编写的，
that is firing up the SQL queries to the database system
向数据库系统发送 SQL 查询，
and now to no fault of the application code writer,
现在应用程序代码编写者没有错误，
that's what the application code writer is doing,
这就是应用程序代码编写者做的事情，
effectively writing the code,
有效地编写代码，
that ends up, sending those read write operations to the database,
最终将这些读写操作发送给数据库，
it feels the database system is just corrupting the data,
它感觉是数据库系统在破坏数据，
so that's obviously not what we want of a database system,
这显然不是我们想要的数据库系统，
we want it to be well behaved,
我们希望它表现良好，
we want the final balance, in this case, to be 50 dollars.
我们想要最后的余额，在这种情况下，是 50 美元。
Okay, so how do we deal with these bad system's, system's behavior,
好的，那么我们如何处理这些糟糕的系统行为，
and have the database be coherent,
并使数据库保持一致，
because ultimately the database is the keeper of the records,
因为最终数据库是记录的保管者，
That's the master copy of what you have in the bank account,
这是你在银行账户中的主副本，
and it has to be consistent,
它必须保持一致，
in spite of all these different failure scenarios.
尽管有这些不同的故障场景。
So, one system way,
所以，一种系统方法，
assuming that you don't have power failure,
假设你没有断电，
is to say, okay, the second type of option that I had were,
是说，好的，我有的第二种选择是，
concurrent actions were corrupting each other,
并发操作相互破坏，
is to say,
就是说，
I'm going to have a very simple database system,
我将拥有一个非常简单的数据库系统，
even if two people requested the queries at the same time,
即使两个人同时请求查询，
I will only run the one query at a time,
我一次也只运行一个查询，
I'm going to queue everything up, all the requests I get,
我将把我收到的所有请求都放入队列，
I will run one query at a time
一次只运行一个查询，
and I can get a sensible, correct behavior
这样我就可以获得合理、正确的行为，
for the scenario we just talked about.
针对我们刚才讨论的场景。
I can also start to do things,
我还可以开始做一些事情，
like before a transaction starts,
比如在事务开始之前，
I can make a copy of the entire database,
我可以复制整个数据库，
make all the changes there,
在那里进行所有更改，
and if the transaction complete successfully,
如果事务成功完成，
so didn't have a power failure, all of that other kinds of stuff,
所以没有停电，所有其他类型的事情，
I will overwrite it with a new copy.
我将用新的副本覆盖它。
Both of these are really bad,
这两种方法都非常糟糕，
from they will give you some form of correctness,
因为它们将给你提供某种形式的正确性，
but they're really bad from a performance perspective,
但从性能角度来看，它们非常糟糕，
because it would be a very, very slow database system
因为它将是一个非常非常慢的数据库系统，
and you won't be able to quite use that, right.
你甚至无法使用它。
Today, when you go to Amazon
今天，当你去亚马逊，
and you're checking out your shopping cart,
你在检查你的购物车时，
you know ultimately something going and issuing database transaction records
最终一些事情会发生，发布数据库事务记录，
to debit from your,
从你的借记卡中扣除，
to add to your shopping cart,
添加到你的购物车中，
eventually another transaction gets there,
最终，另一笔交易被发送到那里，
sent to your credit card account to record that,
发送给你的信用卡账户，记录下来，
that amount needs to be debted
这笔金额需要借记，
and all of that works correctly,
所有这些工作都是正确的，
even if multiple people,
即使有多个人，
multiple account holders on the same credit card
同一张信用卡上的多个账户持有人，
are doing the transactions at the same time,
同时进行交易，
multiple shopping carts are getting created.
创建多个购物车。
So we really want to be able to do this at scale,
所以，我们真的希望能够规模化地进行这项工作，
we don't want to do one transactions at a time,
我们不想一次只做一笔交易，
you want to be doing thousands, tens of thousands,
你想要一次处理数千、数万，
if not millions or billions of transactions at a time.
甚至数百万、数十亿的交易。
Okay, so how do we do that,
好的，那我们该怎么做，
that's a really hard problem.
这是个很难解决的问题。
Okay, if we want better utilization for the database hardware,
好的，如果我们希望更好地利用数据库硬件，
we want higher throughput, better response times,
我们需要更高的吞吐量和更快的响应时间，
and of course, we want it to be correct,
当然，我们希望它是正确的，
so that the right thing happens,
让正确的事情发生，
and we'll define what that notion of correctness is.
我们将定义正确的概念是什么。
And in many cases, you also want it to be fair,
在许多情况下，你也希望这是公平的，
so if multiple transactions come at the same time,
所以如果同时有多个事务，
you want all of them to be given that equal chance to complete
你希望所有的事务都有平等的机会完成，
and not just say I'm going to hold two of you in the back forever
而不是说我会永远把你们中的两个留在后面，
and just let the other others go forward, right,
让其他人继续前进，
that's not fair,
这不公平，
you want to have some notion of fairness.
你想要有一些公平的概念。
And some systems may not have that,
有些系统可能不具备这一点，
sometimes you have priorities,
有时你有优先级，
where you say I want high priorities transactions to go through,
你说我想要高优先级的事务完成，
but assuming you want fairness,
但假设你想要公平，
you at least want the capability of having fairness,
你至少想要拥有公平的能力，
how you balance that,
如何平衡，
in terms of partitioning your workload, to let higher priority stuff go
对工作负载进行分区，让优先级较高工作负载先执行，
is a different issue,
是另一个问题，
but you do want the mechanism of fairness to be built into the database system.
但你确实希望将公平机制构建到数据库系统中。
Okay, questions so far,
好的，到目前为止有什么问题，
in terms of what we are trying to achieve.
关于我们试图实现的目标。
Yep.
是的。
We will try to,
我们试着，
we will solve all the issues
我们会解决所有的问题，
except the power failure issue
除了停电问题，
and the power failure issue will be solved,
停电问题会解决，
and we get to all of that solution later on
我们稍后将介绍所有的解决方案，
where the, there's a very subtle issue in the power failure stuff,
在停电方面有一个非常微妙的问题，
which is with all the stuff we'll talk about in the next few lectures,
在接下来的几节课中将讨论的所有问题，
we can make sure that the database record ends up in the right state.
我们可以确保数据库记录最终处于正确的状态。
But if the bank has paid you 25 dollars
但如果银行向你支付了 25 美元，
and there's a power failure,
然后停电了，
there's extra action that is needed,
就需要采取额外的操作，
because that 25 dollars has been a physical action,
因为这 25 美元是物理上的操作，
everything else is a digital action,
其他一切都是数字上的操作，
and to undo that action of paying you 25 dollars,
为了取消支付给你的 25 美元的操作，
when they should not have paid,
他们不应该支付的，
the bank would have to then do a separate transaction in physical space
银行必须在物理空间进行单独的事务，
where they'll send you a letter saying,
他们会给你发一封信，说，
whoops, we accidentally paid you 25 dollars,
哎呀，我们不小心付给了你 25 美元，
but here's what what your bank account is.
但这是你的银行账户。
So there are other ways to do that,
所以，还有其他方法可以做到这个，
we won't,
我们不会，
we will be able to undo all the read and writes,
我们将能够撤销所有读写，
if we don't want them to happen.
如果我们不希望它们发生。
But, you know, if the transaction is,
但是，如果事务是，
pay 25 dollars is a physical action,
支付 25 美元是一个物理操作，
you can't undo it,
你不能撤销它，
you'll undo that by doing other physical actions in the physical world.
你可以通过在物理世界中做其他物理操作来撤销这个。
Okay, similarly,
好的，同样，
if there's a transaction that fired a missile,
如果有一个事务发射了一枚导弹，
you can't undo that missile,
你就不能撤销那枚导弹，
you can't bring that missile back,
你不能撤回那枚导弹，
you have to send an apology letter or something else like that, right.
你必须发一封道歉信或其他类似的东西。
So, or something really bad,
所以，或者一些非常糟糕的事情，
so it's like,
所以就像是，
the undo for physical actions in transactions will require undo in the physical world,
事务中物理操作的撤消将需要在物理世界中撤消，
which we won't cover,
我们不会讨论这个，
and there are mechanisms to do that,
而且有一些机制可以做到这个，
that are business related actions,
那就是与业务相关的操作，
you'll sometimes get a letter from your company saying,
你有时会收到公司发来的一封信，说，
whoops, we made a mistake, sorry about that,
哎呀，我们搞错了，抱歉，
here's what really happened,
事情的真相是这样的，
oh, and by the way, here's a 10 dollars gift card to make up for a mistake.
哦，顺便说一句，这是一张 10 美元的礼品卡来弥补错误。
But all the digital actions that reads and writes,
但所有读写的数字操作，
we will cast them into a very strict structure
我们将把它们转换成一个非常严格的结构，
to guarantee very well defined properties of correctness that we will hold,
以确保我们持有非常明确的正确性属性，
through the mechanisms we'll talk about today and going into the next few lectures.
通过我们将在今天和接下来的几节课讨论的机制。
Great question.
好问题。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好的。
So, we want these arbitrary interleaving of operations and be correct.
所以，我们希望这些操作的任意交错是正确的。
So before we go a little bit further,
所以在我们更进一步之前，
just want to solidify the notion of transactions,
只是想要巩固事务的概念，
you're going to carry out these operations
你要执行这些操作，
and the database that we just talked about
我们刚才谈到的数据库
is only concerned about the read and write operations to the database objects,
只关心对数据库对象的读写操作，
these physical world actions
这些物理世界的操作，
of paying an amount
支付金额，
or you know, starting fighting for missiles, stuff like that,
或者开始发射导弹之类的东西，
those we won't be able to repair,
我们无法修复，
if bad things happen, okay.
如果发生了糟糕的事情。
And there's in the advanced database class,
在高级数据库课程中，
depending upon the material,
根据材料的不同，
that says sometimes we'll talk about stuff like that
有时我们会谈论这样的事情，
and what are compensating transactions and stuff like that that might happen
以及什么是补偿事务和可能发生的事情，
and what people might do as other ways.
以及人们可能会以其他方式做什么。
So, but for the purpose of this class,
所以，但为了这门课的目标，
we'll just look at in this in this many ways,
我们只会从很多方面来看这个，
a more limited scope.
范围更有限。
Reiterating what we talked about,
重申我们所讨论的内容，
we think primarily about read and write operations,
我们主要考虑读写操作，
you notice that in the code that I had,
你注意到，在我的代码中，
there was also a check, there was a subtraction,
有一个检查，有一个减法，
there was math and stuff like that,
有数学之类的东西，
from the perspective of what we want to cover today for transaction management,
从我们今天要讨论的事务管理的角度来看，
all we care about is,
我们所关心的是，
did an object get written, did it get read,
是否有对象被写入，是否被读取，
and do those reads and writes end up interfering with each other in bad ways,
是否这些读写操作最终会以不好的方式相互干扰，
what are those bad ways
这些不好的方式是什么，
and how do we prevent those bad ways?
我们如何防止这些不好的方式？
And how do we prevent those bad ways,
我们如何防止这些不好的方式，
while allowing the maximum number of transactions to work on the system concurrently,
在允许最大数量的事务在系统上并发工作的同时，
that's the hard part.
这正是难点。
Because you already saw there's an easy way,
因为你已经看到有一种简单的方法，
which is to just do one transaction at a time,
那就是一次只做一个事务，
you want to do better than that.
你想要做得更好。
So it's only these objects,
所以只有这些对象，
which we'll just refer to as variables A, B and C,
我们称为变量 A B 和 C ，
but if you want to have a simple model,
但如果你想有一个简单的模型，
you can think of it as a record,
你可以把它想象成一个记录，
but inside a database system,
但是在数据库系统内部，
in this we cover in the advanced database class,
我们在高级数据库类中介绍，
that a could be a column,
A 可以是列，
which is doing things at a finer level of granularity
以更精细的粒度执行操作，
or it could be a page or it could be a file or it could be a database,
也可以是页，也可以是文件或数据库，
some earlier versions of databases,
一些较早版本的数据库，
like Mongo at one point to do concurrency would lock the entire database,
比如 Mongo ，在某一时刻执行并发操作时会锁住整个数据库，
they don't do that now,
他们现在不这么做了，
but the the, the, the set of that object
但是一组对象，
or the A B and C just referred to database objects, right.
或者 A B 和 C 只是指的是数据库对象。
For the purpose of today,
对于今天的目的，
you can think about them as records.
你可以把它们看作是记录。
And everything today in the next two classes will make a lot more sense,
接下来两节课的内容会更有意义，
if you wanted to pick a [] model for that.
如果你选择一个[]模型。
All right.
好的。
How does the database system know that a transaction is started and transaction is ended,
数据库系统如何知道事务开始和事务结束，
in SQL, you can explicitly put a begin transaction statement and an end transaction statement
在 SQL 中，你可以显式地放置一条开始事务语句和一条结束事务语句，
to tell the database system,
告诉数据库系统，
all the stuff that happened in between is a transaction
在这两条语句之间发生的所有事情都是一个事务，
and in between could be multiple SQL queries.
而这两条语句之间可能是多个 SQL 查询。
If you don't have a begin and end transaction,
如果你没有开始和结束事务，
like all the stuff you've been doing in your homework,
就像你在作业中所做的事情，
when you fire up a SQL query,
当你启动一个 SQL 查询，
implicitly, the database system will
数据库系统将隐式地，
put a begin at the beginning of the query
在查询的开始处放置一个开始，
and an end at the end of the query.
在查询的末尾放置一个结束。
But a transaction could be multi queries, right,
但是一个事务可以是多个查询，
you can explicitly put begin and end.
你可以显式地防止开始和结束。
You could also put an explicit ABORT statement,
你还可以放置一个显式的 ABORT 语句，
which is to say,
也就是说，
so, and instead of end, it is called a COMMIT,
不是最终调用 COMMIT ，
which is to say everything I've done from the BEGIN to here,
是说，我从 BEGIN 到这里所做的一切，
please commit it and make its changes permanent,
请提交它，让它的变更持久化，
the other way to end that transaction is to say ABORT,
结束事务的另一种方式是 ABORT ，
so it may be,
所以，它可能是，
I'm trying to make vacation plans,
我可能正在制定度假计划，
so I do a transaction to book flight tickets,
所以我做了一个事务来预订机票，
then I do a little bit of search in the code
然后我在代码中做一点搜索，
to find hotel reservations
找到酒店预订，
and find, whoops, don't have a hotel,
发现没有酒店，
so I could say,
所以我可以说，
oh, ABORT this transaction
哦，取消这个事务，
and ABORT says,
ABORT 表示，
I did some work, reads and writes,
我做了一些工作，读取和写入，
but I don't think I can go further,
但我不认为我能走得更远，
something doesn't look right,
看起来有些不对劲，
ABORT this transaction
取消这个事务，
and you could, the application could be trying again.
应用程序可以再次尝试。
You could explicitly abort the transaction
你可以显式地中止事务，
and sometimes it may be that the database abort for you,
有时可能是数据库为你中止，
because multiple transactions are happening at the same time,
因为多个事务同时发生，
it detects some unsafe condition
它检测到一些不安全的条件，
and says, whoops, I'm going to abort this transaction for you
并说，我要为你中止这个事务，
and you get an ABORT code.
你会得到 ABORT 代码。
From the transaction manager's perspective,
从事务管理器的角度来看，
the module that we are trying to understand and build today,
我们今天试图理解和构建的模块，
it will be presented with a BEGIN transaction,
它将被呈现一个 BEGIN 事务，
bunch of read write actions
一串读写操作，
and eventually it will get a COMMIT or an ABORT action.
最终它将获得一个 COMMIT 或一个 ABORT 操作。
And that's what we have to build in the system code
这就是我们必须在系统代码中构建的，
to, to do transactions,
以进行事务，
so transactions could end by committing
所以事务可以通过提交结束，
or they could end by aborting,
或者可以通过中止结束，
aborting means undo everything that might be done,
中止意味着取消可能完成的一切，
commit says everything I did make it permanent.
提交是说我做的每一件事都让它持久化。
So they can end in those two ways.
所以他们可以以这两种方式结束。
And the ABORT could be self inflicted,
ABORT 可能是自己造成的，
as we talked about,
正如我们所讨论的，
application could have explicitly put an ABORT call,
应用程序可以显式地放入 ABORT 调用，
or it could be that,
或者可能是，
the database system has to abort for some reason
数据库系统由于某种原因而不得不中止，
to do all this safety guarantee that we talked about.
以完成我们所讨论的所有安全保证。
And we'll look at different ways
我们将看到不同方式，
in which ABORT happens inside a database system
在数据库系统中发生的 ABORT ，
over the next couple of lectures.
在接下来的几节课中。
Okay, many of you might have heard of this thing called ACID,
好的，你们中的很多人可能都听说过 ACID ，
it's a cool acronym,
这是个很酷的首字母缩写，
that was,
那是，
that the community came up,
社区想出来的，
with a couple guys who came up with,
几个人想出来的，
to, say what are the properties we want of these transactions.
表示我们想要这些事务的属性是什么。
And the properties are atomicity consistency, isolation and durability.
属性是，原子性、一致性、隔离性和持久性。
So let's go through each one of those,
所以，让我们逐一查看这些内容，
atomicity says,
原子性表示，
I have a transaction that did a whole bunch of read writes,
我有一个事务执行一大堆读写操作，
and, when I say COMMIT,
当我说 COMMIT 时，
everything should have committed to the database
一切都应该提交到数据库中，
or if I say ABORT,
或者如果我说 ABORT ，
nothing should have happened.
则不应该发生任何事情。
So it's like I want this all or nothing property of this transaction,
所以，就像我想要这个事务的全部或没有的属性，
even though lots of reads and writes might have happened,
即使可能发生了很多读取和写入，
in this, in this transaction, right,
在这个事务中，
it it should feel like it's atomic, right,
对它应该感觉到它是原子的，
so it's very much like,
所以这非常像，
what you see with atomic instructions in, in, in processors,
你在处理器中看到的原子指令，
but now this is for multiple reads and writes,
但现在这是针对多个读取和写入的，
those reads and writes may be spilling data to disk,
这些读写可能会将数据溢出到磁盘，
so it's a much higher granularity, right,
所以这是一个更高粒度的问题，
so much harder problem.
所以是更难的问题。
Consistency says,
一致性表示，
consistency is a little weird one,
一致性是一个有点奇怪的问题，
and I'm actually going to go to that last,
我将讨论最后讨论这个问题，
let me go to isolation
让我去隔离性，
and I'll come back to consistency.
我会回来一致性。
Isolation says,
隔离性表示，
if two transactions,
如果两个事务，
like we have those two debit transactions happening,
比如我们有两个借记事务发生，
withdrawal of 25 dollars from the bank account for you and your significant other,
从你和你的另一半的银行账户中提取 25 美元，
we want those to not interfere with each other,
我们希望这些不会相互干扰，
it should feel like each transaction happened by itself.
它应该让人感觉每个事务都是自己发生的。
So even though we don't want to run one transaction at a time,
所以，即使我们不想一次运行一个事务，
we want the illusion of the system running one transaction at a time,
我们也希望系统一次运行一个事务的错觉，
it should feel like,
这应该让我感觉，
when my transaction ran,
当我的事务运行时，
I had the whole system to myself,
整个系统都是我自己拥有的，
and nothing else interfered with me.
也没有其他东西干扰我。
Does that make sense?
这能理解吗？
So it's like I should feel no one interfered with my work.
所以我应该觉得没有人干扰我的工作。
Durability says that,
持久性表示，
if the database comes back to me and says,
如果数据库返回给我并说，
I've committed your transaction,
我已经提交了你的事务，
after that,
在这之后，
even if there's some failure, the disk fails or the memory fails,
即使出现故障，磁盘故障或内存故障，
I should be able to recover that state of the database,
我也应该能够恢复数据库的该状态，
with all the commit information in that.
带着其中所有的提交信息。
So if I had changed the final value of the bank account to 75,
所以，如果我将银行帐户的最终值更改为 75 ，
the database said I've committed your transaction, right,
数据库说我已经提交了你的事务，
that commit call came back with a green signal
那个提交调用返回时发出绿色信号，
and then there's a power failure,
然后出现停电，
when I bring back the machine,
当我把机器拿回来时，
I should see 75 in there,
我应该看到里面有 75 ，
not 100 which was the value it started with.
而不是它一开始的值 100 。
Now, going back to consistency,
现在，回到一致性上来，
and I waited for that,
我一直在等待，
because I'll just put a little labels around,
因为我会贴上一些标签，
how we go about doing things like that.
我们如何做这样的事情。
Consistency is this weird thing, that says,
一致性是一个奇怪的东西，它表示，
if the database starts consistent, as for some definition,
如果数据库开始是一致的，就像某些定义一样，
then it should end in that same consistent state.
那么它应该以同样的一致状态结束。
Now, that also seems vague, right?
现在，这看起来也很含糊，对吧？
So what does it mean that the database started consistent,
那么，数据库开始保持一致性是什么意思，
in SQL, there are things,
在 SQL 中，有一些东西，
like you can define a primary key, foreign key, right,
比如你可以定义主键，外键，
you've already done that,
你已经做过了，
SQL also has these things called constraints,
SQL 也有这些称为约束的东西，
where you can say, at all and things called checks,
其中你可以说，称为检查的东西，
so a check might say,
所以，检查可能会说，
the price, I've got a price field in a table,
我在一张表里有一个 price 字段，
and that price should never be greater than a hundred,
这个 price 永远不应该超过 100 ，
and the database is required,
数据库需要，
whenever any updates happen to the database system
每当数据库系统发生任何更新时，
to make sure those things hold true.
以确保这些东西为真。
So consistently really says,
所以一致性真正表示，
if the application has specified in the SQL DDL,
如果应用程序已经在 SQL DDL 中指定了，
all the things that they want the database to hold correct,
它们希望数据库正确保存的所有内容，
then, the database transaction shouldn't mess that up.
然后，数据库事务不应该弄乱这些。
And the main ways in which that happens is by checks, primary keys,
发生这种情况的主要方式是通过检查，主键，
and you can also define, ah, ah, checks outside
而且你还可以定义外部检查，
tables and other ways of defining constraints,
表和其他定义约束的方式，
and you really want all of that to hold.
你真的希望这一切都能保持下去。
So it's sort of weird,
所以这有点奇怪，
but it says if the application has defined the structure of the database correctly,
但它表明应用程序正确地定义了数据库的结构，
using everything that SQL allows with these checks,
并使用了 SQL 允许的所有这些检查，
the transaction management,
事务管理，
everything that we do here, shouldn't mess that up.
我们在这里所做的一切都不应该弄乱。
If I said A plus B must always equal to 100
如果我说 A 加上 B 必须总是等于 100 ，
and someone modified A,
有人修改了 A ，
and modified B in the appropriate way,
并以适当的方式修改了 B ，
so that it is still equal to 100 in a single transaction,
它在单个事务中仍然等于 100 ，
the transaction shouldn't violate anything and, and change that constraint,
事务不应违反任何内容，并更改该约束，
so it should maintain that correctness.
所以，它应该保持这种正确性。
And we'll come back to it,
我们会回到这个问题上来，
it sounds a little vague,
这听起来有点含糊，
but in many ways,
但在很多方面，
that C was fitted into that ACID definition,
C 都符合 ACID 的定义，
because the real key things that the database done is AID,
因为数据库真正做的关键事情是 AID ，
but if the acronym was AID,
但是如果首字母缩写是 AID ，
then it didn't sound as good as ACID,
那么它听起来就没有 ACID 那么好听了，
and this was done when hippies were ruling the Bay Area and Europe
这是在嬉皮士统治湾区和欧洲的时候做的，
and they wanted acid everywhere.
他们想要到处都是酸。
So that's the, that's my understanding of how C was plugged in.
这就是我对 C 是如何插入的理解。
We'll talk about different mechanisms,
我们将讨论不同的机制，
and those are what you see in those blue bubble.
这些就是你在蓝色气泡中看到的。
Autonomity and durability will require this mechanism to redo and undo stuff,
自主性和持久性将需要这种机制来重做和撤销东西，
oh, I've changed A and I've pushed it out to disk,
哦，我修改了 A ，我把它推到了磁盘上，
I've pushed it out from my buffer pool to disk,
我已经将它从我的缓冲池推送到磁盘，
oh, but I need to abort that transaction,
哦，但我需要取消那个事务，
so how do I undo that?
那么我怎么才能撤销这个呢？
Oh, I committed a transaction with a new value of A,
哦，我用 A 的新值提交了一个事务，
but it's still sitting my buffer pool,
但它仍然位于我的缓冲池中，
it didn't make it to disk,
它没有被放到磁盘上，
I need to redo the disk copy,
我需要重做磁盘复制，
so the redo and undo mechanisms is what the A and D provides,
所以 A 和 D 提供了重做和撤消机制，
we'll use things that we'll see today and in the next lecture that cover that.
我们将使用，今天和下一节课中讨论的内容。
As I said,
正如我所说的，
consistency is provided by making sure there are integrity constraints defined in your SQL DDL
一致性是通过确保在你的 SQL DDL 中定义了完整性约束来提供的，
and the transaction management system shouldn't violate that.
并且事务管理系统不应该违反该约束。
Isolation is done by something called concurrency control,
隔离是通过称为并发控制的东西来完成的，
which we, which we will also look at,
我们也将讨论这一点，
and locking and other mechanisms will come into play there.
锁和其他机制将在那里发挥作用。
So we're going to dig into each one of these,
所以，我们将深入研究其中的每一个，
so let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Alright, so that's our agenda,
好的，这就是我们的日程，
dive into each of these four components.
深入研究这四个组成部分中的每一个。
So, atomicity of transactions,
所以，事务的原子性，
there are two possible outcomes for executing a transaction,
执行事务有两种可能的结果，
it either commits or it aborts, right,
它要么提交，要么被中止，
and the aborts could be explicitly,
中止可以是显示地，
triggered by the application,
由应用程序触发，
or it could be something that the database is something unsafe,
或者可能是数据库不安全，
I need to abort you
我需要中止你，
and then that transaction could restart and reissue that SQL statement,
然后事务可以重新启动并重新发出该 SQL 语句，
and the DBMS needs to provide this all or nothing [] atomic property of these transactions.
DBMS 需要提供这些事务这种全部或没有的原子属性。
So let's make it a little bit more concrete,
所以让我们把它变得更具体一点，
we've been playing around with examples,
我们一直在举这个例子，
so we look at a couple scenarios as we dig into this.
所以我们在深入研究这个时，看几个场景，
We take 100 dollars out of an account,
我们从一个账户中提取 100 美元，
but the database system aborts the transaction before we transfer it, right,
但在我们转账之前，数据库系统中止事务，
so we want to make sure, that that is reflected correctly.
所以我们要确保这是正确反映的。
Scenario two is,
第二种场景是，
we take 100 dollars out of an account,
我们从一个账户中提取 100 美元，
but then there's a power failure,
但随后出现了停电，
before we transfer that.
在我们转账之前。
We've kind of seen both of these transactions,
我们已经看到了这两个事务，
but just giving you more examples of what that should be,
但只是给你更多的例子来说明应该是什么，
and, you know, we have to determine what's the correct state of the account
而且我们必须确定账户的正确状态，
after both these transaction aborts.
在这两个事务中止之后。
So, how can we do some of this stuff,
所以，我们怎么能做一些这样的事情呢，
the atomity part can be done in one of two ways,
原子性部分可以通过两种方式之一来完成，
logging and shadowing,
日志和跟踪，
one way is to log everything that we do,
一种方法是记录我们所做的一切，
so if I'm recording all my actions,
所以，如果我记录我的所有操作，
the minute I change a value from 100 to 75,
我修改某个值从 100 到 75 的那一刻，
I can record that my value was 100,
我可以记录我的值是 100 ，
I change it to 75,
我把它改成 75 ，
my before value was 100, after value is 75,
我之前的值是 100 ，之后的值是 75 ，
now I can take those logs
现在我可以获取这些日志，
and I can maintain those log records
我可以维护这些日志记录，
and I can store those log records in memory
我可以在内存中存储这些日志记录，
and then appropriate points move it out to disk,
然后适当的点将其移出到磁盘，
once it moves into disk,
一旦它移动到磁盘中，
I know it is going to be there,
我知道它就会在那里，
it will survive that power failure.
它将在停电后幸存下来。
If I don't think I can trust a single disk to hold that log,
如果我认为我不能信任单个磁盘来保存日志，
many times people will use disk mirroring,
很多时候人们会使用磁盘镜像，
remember, we talked about disk mirroring a couple lectures ago,
还记得，我们在几节课前讨论过磁盘镜像，
so if there are two disks that will have a copy of that same file I write,
所以，如果有两个磁盘将具有我写入的同一文件的副本，
but it's actually being written in twice in two places,
但实际上它在两个位置被写入两次，
so that if one fails, I still have that other copy,
所以如果其中一个出现故障，我还有另一个副本，
that if both fail, you'd have to make a third copy and so on,
如果两个都出现故障，你将不得不创建第三个副本，以此类推。
so you have to decide what failure you can tolerate.
所以你必须决定你能容忍什么样的失败。
But once a log hits the disk,
但是，一旦日志到达磁盘，
you kind of know you can recover from that
你知道可以从中恢复，
and reconstruct the state of the database.
并重建数据库的状态。
And we'll talk about the protocol as, as in two lectures from now,
我们将在接下来的两节课中讨论协议，
how we go and make that happen.
我们将如何实现这个。
But logging is the mechanism that most database systems will use,
但是日志是大多数数据库系统将使用的机制，
to go and record the changes that are happening.
去记录发生的变化。
All right.
好的。
Does that make sense? Questions?
这能理解吗？有问题吗？
No, don't confuse this with log structured file system,
不，不要将其与日志结构文件系统混淆，
is that what you are thinking,
这是你认为的那样吗，
it will look like, that way is different.
它看起来方式是不同的。
So a lot of this origin, origin in the 70 and 80s,
所以这个很多起源于 70 和 80 年代，
it's a file of records,
这是一个记录的文件，
but the records are going to be variable length
但记录的长度是可变的，
and the structure will have a certain set of common fields,
结构将有一组特定的通用字段，
but think of it as a file,
但可以将其视为一个文件，
with a bunch of variable,
包含一堆可变的，
with some fixed length components and a whole bunch of variable,
具有固定长度[分量]和一大堆变量，
and it's sitting in a file that will often be called a log file
它位于一个通常被称为日志文件的文件中，
and it's basically going to be written sequentially from first to the end,
基本上它将从头到尾按顺序写入，
and it will be, it will have its own buffer management,
它将拥有自己的缓冲区管理，
so it, the recent pages will be in the buffer pool,
所以最近的页面将位于缓冲池中，
at certain points, we will have to tell that,
在这个点上，我们必须说出这个，
the buffer pool,
缓冲池，
to say,
也就是说，
I cannot commit this transaction to this page you have here in memory,
我不能将此事务提交到内存中，
that needs to hit to disk,
它需要命中磁盘，
before I can commit this transaction,
在我可以提交这个事务之前，
so we might hold the transactions commit,
所以我们可能会保留事务提交，
we won't return it, utill we have,
我们不会返回，直到我们，
but you can think of it as a file of records,
但是你可以把它想象成一个记录文件，
just like a regular file,
就像一个普通的文件，
but it's got its special structure.
但它有特殊的结构。
Yeah, so the question is,
是的，所以问题是，
if I have a log structured file system,
如果我有一个日志结构的文件系统，
do I need logging,
我是否需要日志，
a log structured file system just works for that file,
一个日志结构文件系统只对那个文件有效，
so in a database system,
所以，在一个数据库系统中，
I may have 100 tables,
我可能有 100 个表，
a transaction we have updated in five different places,
我们在五个不同的位置更新了一个事务，
I need a global log logging mechanism to deal with that.
我需要一个全局日志机制来处理这个问题。
So traditionally what will be done,
所以，传统上做的，
I have a log file,
我有一个日志文件，
which is going to keep these changes,
它将保留所有这些变更，
for all the changes that are happening across,
为所有发生的更改，
not just for a single file.
而不仅仅是单个文件。
So log structured file system does make sense,
所以，日志结构化文件系统确实有意义，
they have similar elements to the types of mechanisms,
它们具有类似的元素到机制类型，
that you're trying to do redo and undo type of things,
与你尝试执行的重做和撤消类型的东西相比，
but they are on a pool file basis,
但它们在的文件基础池中，
they may not be the right structure for it,
它们可能不是适合它的结构，
they don't necessarily have all the buffer stuff,
它们不一定拥有所有缓冲的东西，
so it's good for certain applications and file system,
所以，它适用于某些应用程序和文件系统，
but for database systems, we're going to need something different
但是对于数据库系统，我们需要一些不同的东西，
and we need it across different files, right.
我们需要跨不同的文件。
You might [pull] all our operations, too,
你可能也会取消我们的所有操作，
so we'll talk about all of that as we go into details,
所以我们将在详细讨论时讨论所有这些操作，
but that's a good point,
但这是一个很好的观点，
why am I, you know, why do the operating systems guys talk about log structured file systems,
为什么我，为什么操作系统的人谈论日志结构文件系统，
they're very similar elements to that,
它们是非常相似的元素，
can we use that,
我们能用这个吗，
we need to worry about transactions that update records across multiple different tables,
我们需要担心跨多个不同表更新记录的事务，
which may be in multiple different files sitting in the file system,
这些表可能位于文件系统中的多个不同文件中，
and still be atomic across those files,
并且这些文件之间仍然是原子的，
so it's different.
所以这是不同的。
So in many ways,
所以，在许多方面，
we have to do a little bit,
我们必须做一些事情，
we have a harder problem to solve.
我们有一个更难解决的问题。
Great question, though,
不过，这是个很好的问题，
other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Okay.
好的。
All right, so logging is used, by nearly every database system,
好的，所以几乎每个数据库系统都在使用日志记录，
what's the alternative, you might ask,
你可能会问，还有其他选择吗，
in the very early days before logging
在日志之前的很早的日子里，
and all the details about logging where it really worked out,
以及所有关于日志真正有效的细节，
a very easy way to kind of do this stuff was to do shadow paging,
做这些事情的一个非常简单的方法是进行影子分页，
it's like copy-on-write type of thing, right,
它就像是写入时复制的东西，
and you'll see that in many applications, you'll see similar concepts by the way,
顺便说一句，你们会在许多应用程序中看到类似的概念，
those of you've taken operating systems
你们中的那些人使用过操作系统，
or I've dug into that,
或者我已经深入研究过了，
I going to find a lot of common things between database systems and operating systems,
我要找出数据库系统和操作系统之间的许多共同之处，n
we already hit latches and locks,
我们已经遇到了 latch 和 lock ，
they try to do different things,
它们试图做不同的事情，
but a lot of database systems are going to be on larger things,
但许多数据库系统将存储更大的内容，
lots of files, lots of data,
大量的文件和大量的数据，
and in some set, the mechanisms are going to be different than, in my view, often richer.
在我看来，在某些情况下，机制将不同于，通常更丰富。
So shadowing is,
所以影子是，
okay, I'm gonna make change to a record on a page,
好的，我要更改页面上的记录，
you know what,
你知道的，
I'm just going to make a new copy of the page
我只需要创建一个新的页面副本，
and make the changes there,
然后在那里进行更改，
that way, if I need to undo stuff,
这样，如果我需要撤消某些内容，
I'll just go back to the old page,
我只需返回到旧页面，
and I've got both my before and after copy for the entire page.
我有整个页面的前后副本。
Now, of course, some systems still do that,
当然，现在一些系统仍然这样做，
but it's not a good idea,
但这不是一个好主意，
it's less efficient,
它的效率较低，
if I just wanted to change one byte in one page,
如果我只想在一个页面中更改一个字节，
I'm going to make an entire copy of the page,
我会创建整个页面的副本，
so that's obviously wasteful.
这显然是浪费的。
I still need to go and clean things up
我仍然需要去清理东西，
and merge things up others before,
把东西合并到之前的上面，
you know it, if I've got one page which has got a hot record,
如果我有一个页面有一个热门记录，
and let's say it's the counter,
假设它是计数器，
that says how many SKUs do I have for the pink Barbie doll,
显示我的粉色芭比娃娃有多少 SKU ，
that's really popular,
那真的很受欢迎，
every time someone buys that Barbie doll,
每次有人买那个芭比娃娃，
that counter will change,
计数器就会改变，
I'm going to make copies and copies of the page, right,
我要创建这个页面的副本一份又一份，
so if I've got a million Barbie dolls,
所以如果我有一百万个芭比娃娃，
I'll have a million copies.
我就会有一百万个副本。
By the way, counters in database systems aren't kept that way,
顺便说一句，数据库系统中的计数器不是以这种方式保存的，
they are done with more semantic components using commutative action,
它们是用更多的语义成分来完成的，使用[交换]动作，
that's just a side comment,
这只是一个次要的评论，
also an encouragement to take the advanced database class
也是鼓励参加高级数据库课程，
to talk about more complex mechanisms
来讨论更复杂的机制，
to make transactions go even faster and better.
以使事务进行得更快、更好。
But you get the idea that shadow paging can very quickly,
但你会明白影子分页可以非常快，
it's a cheap mechanism,
这是一种廉价的机制，
easy to implement, but is problematic,
易于实施，但存在问题，
logging is superior,
日志更好，
and that's what most database systems use.
这也是大多数数据库系统使用的。
So let's get to the C part,
所以让我们来看看 C 部分，
which has always been a little difficult to explain,
这部分一直很难解释，
but hopefully with this slide, it will start to become better.
但是希望有了这张幻灯片会开始变得更好。
It's essentially saying,
这实质上是说，
I have a contract between the database system and I
我和数据库系统之间有一个契约，
as an application programmer.
作为一名应用程序程序员，
have a contract with you, the database system,
与数据库系统签订契约，
that I'll tell you what I want in the application
我将告诉你我想要在应用程序中实现什么，
through my sql statement, my primary key constraints, my checks
通过我的 SQL 语句，我的主键约束，我的检查，
and other things that I want in the system
和其他我想要在系统中实现的东西，
and don't mess it up.
不要弄乱它。
if those constraint held before the transaction started,
如果在事务开始之前持有这些约束，
then the transaction ran,
然后，事务运行，
and it may have touched a million objects,
它可能已经触及了一百万个对象，
read and write millions of objects across hundreds of tables,
读写数百个表中的数百万个对象，
once you say it's committed,
一旦你说它被提交了，
all those constraints must still be true.
所有这些约束必须仍然是真的。
Okay, if one of my constraints was,
好的，如果我的约束之一是，
the sum of all the columns in this, the in the price field is less than 100,
价格字段中所有列的总和小于 100 ，
that should still be true,
它应该仍然是真的，
if I say all the column A should add up to be a million
如果我说所有的列 A 加起来应该是一百万，
and exactly be a million
就应该是一百万，
and lots of changes happen to different, to different values in that column A,
那个 A 列的两个不同的值发生了很大的变化，
that should still hold true
那应该仍然是真的，
that sum should still be a million at the end of it.
在它结束的时候，总和应该仍然是一百万。
And I've specified that through my constraint,
我已经通过我的约束规定了这个，
that should still still hold true.
这个应该仍然是真的。
Now, the transaction management is not going to do anything different,
现在，事务管理不会做任何不同的事情，
as you'll see,
如你所见，
we just have to make sure that the atomicity holds,
我们只需要确保保持原子性，
the AID components hold
保持 AID 组件，
and constraint consistency will just get taken care of, right,
约束一致性将得到正确处理，
if we don't mess that up.
如果我们不弄乱的话。
So that's why C kind of like plugged into this asset stuff,
这就是为什么 C 是连接这些东西的原因，
the transaction mechanisms we'll talk about today in the next two lectures,
我们今天将在接下来的两节课中讨论的事务机制，
aren't going to directly address C,
不会直接涉及 C ，
it's the responsibility of the application programmer to define those constraints correctly.
正确定义这些约束是应用程序程序员的责任。
To make matters even more confusing,
让事情变得更加混乱，
a little while back close to a decade ago,
回到大约十年前的一段时间，
there's all this excitement about this thing called eventual consistency,
所有这些关于最终一致性的东西都很令人兴奋，
even though it has the word consistency,
尽管它有一致性这个词，
has nothing to do with the consistency that we just defined here as a C in acid,
但与我们在这里 ACID 中定义的的 C 的一致性无关，
that consistency was a model saying,
那个一致性是一个模型表示，
oh these transactions are hard in distributed systems,
这些事务在分布式系统中很难实现，
it becomes very tough to do that,
要做到这个变得非常困难，
though now we have figured things out
尽管现在我们已经弄清楚了，
and how to do things in distributed systems well too,
以及如何在分布式系统中做事情，
but at that time,
但在那个时候，
when people were building these systems
当人们在构建这些系统时，
and largely the systems were being built by people who hadn't taken a database course,
这些系统主要是由没有学习过数据库课程的人构建的，
that was the problem.
这就是问题所在。
They said the best way we can make this happen is to be eventually consistent,
他们说，我们能做到这个的最好方法是最终一致性，
so let the changes happen
所以，让更改发生，
and then eventually if a two transactions make changes to A,
然后最终如果两个事务对 A 进行更改，
eventually they would be the same.
最终它们将是相同的。
So if that 25 dollars withdrawal from two accounts happening simultaneously,
所以，如果从两个账户同时提取 25 美元，
it's like eventually they will end up to be 50,
最终它们就会变成 50 美元，
but for a while even though both have been paid 25 dollars,
但有一段时间，即使两人都获得了 25 美元，
you read the value, you will see 75,
你读到的值，你会看到 75 ，
so the eventual consistency model is,
所以最终的一致性模型是，
don't trust the value, eventually it'll be right,
不要相信它的值，最终它会是正确的，
but the question from the application perspective is,
但从应用程序的角度来看，问题是，
how long do I have to wait for it,
我需要等待多长时间，
and how do I know when something is right or not,
我怎么知道什么是对的，什么是错的，
and there were early days when people were building these applications,
在早期，人们还在构建这些应用程序，
with the venture consistency where you'd have your Facebook APP,
有了 Facebook 应用程序的[风险]一致性，
you'd post a message,
你发布一条消息，
and your friend would see it,
你的朋友会看到，
you would refresh here and it would be gone,
你在这里刷新，它会消失，
because eventually it would be there,
因为它最终会在那里，
but just fetched from a different server that hadn't gotten your message,
但只是从没有收到你的消息的不同服务器获取，
your first connection was made to server one,
你的第一个连接连接到服务器一，
second connection for refreshment is something else,
第二个刷新的连接是另一个，
it hasn't gotten the update.
它还没有得到更新。
So as you can imagine,
所以，正如你可以想象的，
that became very hard for application programmers to do,
这对应用程序程序员来说变得非常困难，
the whole point of having database systems or data platforms deal with transactions is,
让数据库系统或数据平台处理事务的全部意义在于，
so I, as an application programmer, don't have to deal with it.
我作为一名应用程序程序员，我不必处理它。
So it's now universally accepted, that it's a pretty bad idea,
所以，现在人们普遍认为这是一个非常糟糕的想法，
unless there you have very strict requirements for performance,
除非你对性能有非常严格的要求，
that require you to do nothing but just that.
要求你只做这件事。
But it is not the go to way to build data platforms by saying,
但这不是构建数据平台的方法说，
you, the application person, start worrying about transactions.
你作为应用程序人员开始担心事务。
Bunch of systems still use eventual consistency,
很多系统仍然使用最终一致性，
but I'll briefly flash the Spanner paper,
但我将简单地展示一下 Spanner 论文，
which globally is using things,
它在全球范围内使用，
that are even stronger than ACID.
甚至比 ACID 更强。
And then again, if you take the advanced database class,
再说一次，如果你上了高级数据库课，
we talk about stuff like that over there, is there.
我们会在那里讨论类似的东西。
So it's not that systems don't use that today,
所以，这并不是说今天的系统不使用它，
I'm just saying,
我只是说，
in my view, it's not a good idea,
在我看来，这不是一个好主意，
to use that as a default way to build a data platform.
将它作为构建数据平台的默认方式。
There's still some reasons why you may want to do that,
你可能想这么做还是有一些原因的，
but it's not the way you should say,
但这不是你应该说的方式，
I'm going to make my database by design eventual consistency,
我要让我的数据库在设计上保持最终一致性，
because, I didn't think of doing other ways of doing full transactions,
因为，我没有想过做其他方式来做完整的事务，
their performance,
它们的性能，
obviously you can get more performance with eventual consistency,
显然，最终一致性可以获得更高的性能，
there's no doubt about that.
这一点是毫无疑问的。
Sorry for this question, but.
对于这个问题我很抱歉，但是。
I close my ears, everyone close their ears, no.
我闭上耳朵。大家都闭上耳朵，没有。
Basically, so what is eventual consistency?
基本上，什么是最终一致性？
Eventual consistency says,
最终一致性是指，
eventually all the values will be the right values.
最终所有的值都会是正确的值。
So, it'll feel like you got your transactions,
所以，它就像你获得了你的事务，
but for a while, you may see inconsistent value,
但在一段时间内，你可能会看到不一致的值，
so that's what eventual consistency is.
这就是最终一致性。
So an application gets there, like reaching in the []
所以，就像应用程序到达那里，
and it might just be wrong.
而它可能是错误的。
Yeah, as I said,
是的，就像我说的，
you may see 75 for a while,
你可能会短期看到 75 美元，
then it should be 50,
然后它应该是 50 美元，
both of you, you're standing next to each other on two side by side ATM machines,
你们并排站在两台并排的 ATM 机边上，
both of you got your 25 bucks
你们两个都拿到了 25 美元，
and you will say, oh, 75 is in the bank,
你们会说，哦， 75 美元在银行里，
which is not true,
但事实并非如此，
and the bank will say,
银行会说，
you know what, it was actually 50 we sent you that,
实际上我们寄给你的是 50 美元，
eventually it will be the right amount.
最终会是正确的金额。
But as you can see, it's hard, right,
但如你所见，这很难，
you don't want that in your application.
你不希望在你的应用程序中出现这种情况。
Yep.
是的。
Yeah, another question?
是的，还有问题吗？
No, there are other [] has eventual consistency,
不，还有其他[]有最终的致性，
other systems, too, have eventual consistency models.
其他系统也有最终一致性模型。
Put this term out, yes.
把这个词拿出来，是的。
Ah, but, but there there was a whole time where people were saying,
但是有一段时间人们说，
we don't need SQL,
我们不需要 SQL ，
we don't need transactions,
我们不需要事务，
no SQL, eventual consistency that hasn't quite worked out for those people.
没有 SQL ，最终一致性对这些人来说并不是很有效。
So I'm not saying there's no call for eventual consistency,
所以，我并不是说没有必要保持最终的一致性，
I'm saying that's not what you should design for by default,
我的意思是，默认情况下，这不是你应该为之设计的，
unless you know what you're getting into,
除非你知道你要面对的是什么，
and now you're going to have to put the complexity in the application.
而现在你将不得不将复杂性放在应用程序中。
Okay?
好的？
So there is still some place for it,
所以，它仍然有一些位置，
but not like that's not the default setting.
但这并不是默认设置。
So, alright, let's go find my mouse again,
所以，好的，让我们再去找我的鼠标，
there we go.
我们走吧。
All right, so isolation of transactions.
好的，事务的隔离性。
So we are still on I,
所以我们仍然在 I ，
users submit transaction,
用户提交事务，
each transaction executes as if it is running by itself,
每个事务的执行方式就像它自己运行一样，
and obviously it's an easier programming model as we talked about,
正如我们所说的，显然它是一种更容易的编程模型，
and the DBMS is going to do its stuff
而 DBMS 将做它的事情，
to give this one-at-a-time or isolation as a principle.
给这个每次一个或隔离的原则。
So, how does it do that?
所以，它是如果做到这个的？
There are two classes of methods,
这里有两类方法，
and again today I'm just going to outline it at a high level,
再次，今天我从高层次上概述它，
we'll get into the details of it in the next lecture.
我们将在下次课程中详细介绍。
The two classes,
两节课，
one is pessimistic, which is to say,
一个是悲观的，也就是说，
even before I let a read and write happen,
即使在我允许读写发生之前，
I'm going to be pessimistic,
我是悲观的，
if I think something bad's going to happen,
如果我认为会发生一些不好的事情，
I'm going to hold you back,
我会阻止你，
hold you that transaction that I think is going to start this bad action back,
阻止我认为会开始这个不好的操作的事务，
and we'll see how that happens in a little bit with, with a couple of mechanisms.
我们将通过几个机制来看看这是如何发生的。
The second way is basically to do something called optimistic concurrency,
第二种方式基本上就是做一个叫乐观并发的事情，
which is to say,
也就是说，
I think every life is good,
我觉得每个生活都是好的，
I'm going to let every transaction go through,
我要让每一个事务都通过，
I'll still provide the isolation principle,
我仍然会提供隔离原则，
so that they don't interfere with each other,
这样它们就不会相互干扰，
but I'm going to do that by checking,
但我会通过检查来做到这个，
assuming everything is going to go well,
假设一切都会顺利进行，
so it's like everyone go to your reads and writes,
所以，就像每个人都去你的读写，
I'll keep track of it, go make your changes,
我会跟踪它，去做你的变更，
but before you're ready to commit,
但在你准备提交之前，
I will do some checks
我会做一些检查，
to see if you guys interfered with each other,
看看你们是否相互干扰，
all of you guys,
你们所有的人，
all of you transactions that were running together simultaneously.
你们所有同时运行的事务。
So optimistic is most transactions don't conflict with each other,
所以，乐观是，大多数事务并不相互冲突，
so I can get a higher performance system by being optimistic,
所以，我可以通过乐观获得更高性能的系统，
that most things will work out,
大多数事情都会解决，
It will still be correct,
它仍然是正确的，
so it will make sure bad things don't happen,
所以它将确保不会发生不好的事情，
but it's a different philosophy.
但这是一种不同的哲学。
All right, so.
好的，所以。
Let's start digging into a couple of examples.
让我们开始深入研究几个例子。
Now, as we know, transactions are going to be cast in terms of these read write operations
现在，我们知道，事务将被转换为这些读写操作，
and now you're starting to see some of the BEGIN and COMMIT calls that are coming in.
现在你开始看到一些 BEGIN 和 COMMIT 调用进入。
So, T1 is a transaction,
所以， T1 是一个事务，
that subtracting,
那个减法，
that moving 100 dollars from bank account A to bank account B,
它将 100 美元从银行帐户 A 转移到银行帐户 B ，
and T2 is a transaction,
T2 是一个事务，
that's adding 6% interest to all the bank accounts
为所有银行帐户增加 6% 利息，
and assume this is a small bank,
假设这是一家小银行，
so it just has two bank accounts,
所以它只有两个银行帐户，
also keeps the example simple.
还可以使示例保持简单。
What's the possible outcome of running these two?
这两个事务可能的结果是什么？
The two possible outcomes.
两种可能的结果。
One is,
一个是，
assume both A and B, start with 1000 dollars,
假设 A 和 B 都是，从 1000 美元开始，
if I run A followed by B or B followed by A,
如果我运行 A 在 B 之前或 B 在 A 之前，
I'm going to get two different execution strategies,
我会得到两种不同的执行策略，
but eventually A plus B should be 2000 and 6%,
但最终 A 加上 B 应该是 2000 6% ，
of that means that the total bank account,
这意味着总的银行账户，
across those two banks,
跨越这两家银行，
should be 2120.
应该是 2120 。
So, that's what we want to end up with.
所以，这就是我们想要的结果。
Now, what we are going to look at next,
现在，接下来我们要看的是，
I'm just going to jump into this is,
我将跳到这里是，
with just these two transactions,
只有这两个事务，
I could have a correct isolation property being held
我可以保持正确的隔离属性，
by either running the first transaction first,
通过无论先运行第一个事务，
and running the second transaction first,
和先运行第二个事务，
there are two possible outcomes,
这里有两种可能的结果，
T1 runs first followed by T2 or vice versa.
T1 在 T2 之前运行，或者相反。
And so here you can see,
所以，在这里你可以看到，
one example, where the value of A is 954 and B is 1166,
一个例子， A 的值是 954 ， B 是 1166 ，
that will correspond to having done the 100 dollars transfer first, then adding 6%,
这相当于首先完成了 100 美元的转账，然后加上 6% ，
and the other one is doing it the other way around.
另一个是反过来做的。
So either one of those by the isolation principle is correct,
所以，根据隔离原则，这两种中的任何一种都是正确的，
if both transactions are in the system at the same time,
如果两个事务同时在系统中，
we are okay,
我们没有问题，
we as a transaction management system
作为一个事务管理系统，
are okay in picking that order,
我们可以选择那个顺序，
so let's just look at it more visually
所以，让我们更直观地看待它，
and that might make sense.
这可能是有意义的。
There is this notion of a serial execution,
有一种串行执行的概念，
and the serial execution diagram that we'll see in the next 10 or 15 slides,
我们将在接下来的 10 到 15 张幻灯片中看到的串行执行图，
all are going to have time going from top to the bottom,
所有都有时间从上到下，
so, imagine you are the machine
想象一下，你是机器，
and you're watching transactions come at you.
你看着事务向你过来。
And isolation basically says,
隔离性基本上是说，
if this execution is such that,
如果这个执行是这样的，
you can show me, prove to me,
你可以向我展示，向我证明，
that no matter what you do,
无论你做什么，
whichever order you allowed the transaction,
无论你允许了哪一个事务，
it feels like one happened before the other
比如一个发生在另一个之前，
and that one happened before the other could be,
一个发生在另一个之前可以是，
all of T1 happened followed by T2, in this case,
T1 发生在 T2 之前，在这个例子中，
which is the example on the left,
这是左边的例子，
which is when you end up with A equal to 954 and B is 1166
当你最终得到 A 等于 954 ， B 等于 1166 ，
or T2 followed by that,
或 T2 在前，
both of them are correct.
它们都是正确的。
But if you are going to intervene these reads and writes for these two transactions,
但是，如果你要干预这两个事务的这些读写操作，
the database better end up with one of these two correct end states,
数据库最好以这两个正确的结束状态之一结束，
which one, doesn't matter,
哪一个，并不重要，
but it should be one of those two,
但它应该是那两个中的一个，
not, not something else.
而不是别的。
Question?
问题？
No, that's the whole point.
不，这才是重点。
So the question is,
所以问题是，
why are we doing this in parallel,
为什么我们要并行做这件事，
that's the whole point.
这就是重点。
Right now, this a serial execution,
现在，这是一个串行执行，
so T1 happening after T2 in time,
所以在时间上 T1 发生在 T2 之后，
but what we want to do is,
但我们想要做的是，
to imagine I've got two cores in this server
假设我在这台服务器中有两个核心，
and today's servers have 40 cores
而今天的服务器有 40 个核心，
and database machines sometimes have hundreds of machines,
数据库机器有时有数百台机器，
I don't want to be just running one transaction at a time,
我不想一次只运行一个事务，
I want to be able to do as many actions at any given point in time,
我希望能够在任何给定的时间点执行尽可能多的操作，
I want to do as many things as possible,
我想做尽可能多的事情，
because I want to use all the hardware I have access to,
因为我想使用我有权访问的所有硬件，
that way I can get more transactions in the system,
所以我可以在系统中获得更多事务，
higher throughput and lower latency potentially.
更高的吞吐量和更低的潜在延迟。
No, no, no, we will not lower the standard,
不，不，不，我们不会降低标准，
so hold on, we will not lower the standard,
所以等等，我们不会降低标准，
we are definitely changing the standard a little bit
我们肯定会稍微改变一下标准，
to say any permutation of T1 followed by T2 is allowed, T2,
说 T1 和 T2 的任何排列都是允许的，
T1 and T2 can be interchanged,
T1 和 T2 可以互换，
as long as we can prove one did all of its work before the other.
只要我们能证明一个在另一个之前做了所有的工作。
So hold on for two slides,
所以等待两张幻灯片，
you're right, it's like why is it not only one possible way,
你是对的，就像为什么不是只有一种可能的方式，
that T1 should be followed by T2,
T1 在 T2 之前，
if we did that,
如果我们这样做了，
then we would allow less parallelism in the system.
那么我们就会减少系统中的并行性。
So you're going to relax the strict notion of what is correct
所以你要放松严格的概念，什么是正确的，
and this is where there's this notion of strict serializable,
这就是可串行化的严格概念，
which will say,
这意味着，
the transactions should feel like,
事务应该感觉像是，
they [] in the way in which they happen in the physical world,
它们在物理世界中发生的那样[]，
we'll talk about that in the next class a little bit,
我们将在下一节课中讨论一点这个，
and we'll talk about it a lot more in the advanced database class.
我们将在高级数据库课上更详细地讨论这个。
First, let's get a little bit write,
首先，让我们做一点写入，
and this is, by the way, of what most database systems do today,
顺便说一句，这就是今天大多数数据库系统所做的事情，
they will take this slight liberty of [] it,
他们会稍微冒昧地[]一下，
because it's also like T1 and T2 issued at the same time,
因为就像 T1 和 T2 同时发出，
what does it even mean for it to be issued at the same time,
同时发出意味着什么，
they may be in different cities,
他们可能在不同的城市，
if you're sitting next to each other,
如果你们坐在一起，
it's not as if you would be pressing the button exactly at the same second,
你们不会在同一时间按下按钮，
because that doesn't happen,
因为这不会发生，
so it's like what does simultaneous mean.
所以这就像同时是什么意思。
So we're going to be a little bit more relaxed,
所以我们会稍微放松一点，
all we have is to say
我们所能说的是，
for us to be have this proper isolation,
如果我们有这种适当的隔离，
the final values should be one of these two,
最终的值应该是这两个值中的一个，
not a third value.
不是第三个值。
Look at this slide here first, yep,
首先看看这张幻灯片，是的，
so here T T1 starts and does its subtraction of 100,
在这里 T1 开始，减去 100 ，
so now A has the 100 dollars already removed,
现在 A 已经把 100 美元去掉了，
T2 starts and gives 6% interest to the two bank accounts,
T2 启动，产生 6% 的利息到两个银行账户，
but the bank account value for A that it is looking at is 100 dollars short,
但它查看的 A 的银行账户价值还差 100 美元，
and so it ends up with a value of 2114 as the sum total,
所以它最终的值是 2114 作为总和，
which is 6 dollars off from what that original about should be.
这比原来应该是的值少了 6 美元。
So what we want to allow is these two,
所以我们想要允许的是这两个，
the interleaving in the previous slide that is safe,
前一张幻灯片中的交错是安全的，
where you end up with the correct value, even though there's interleaving,
即使有交错，你最终也会得到正确的值，
but this is an example of an unsafe interleaving,
但这是一个不安全交错的例子，
where you ended up with the wrong value, right.
你最终得到了错误的值。
So this is fine,
所以这是好的，
sorry, I was here on the wrong slide here,
抱歉，我看错幻灯片了，
this is fine,
这是好的，
and the question is how do we determine that this is okay,
问题是，我们如何确定这是可以的，
this type of interleaving of actions across different transactions is okay,
这种跨不同事务的操作交错是可以的，
but this one is not.
但这个不可以。
Okay?
好的？
So let's look at, how we go about doing that.
那么让我们来看看，我们是如何做到这个的。
So there's this formal notion of serial schedule,
所以有一个正式的串行调度的概念，
that says a schedule that does not interleave any of the action.
它指的是一个不会交错任何操作的调度。
So we saw that, right,
所以我们看到，
a serial example of, a serial schedule was one,
一个串行调度的例子是，
where you just had all the T1s,
你只有所有的 T1 ，
like here is a serial schedule,
就像这是一个串行调度，
so if we go back,
所以如果我们回去，
this is a serial schedule,
这是一个串行调度，
T1 followed by T2 or T2 followed by T T1.
T1 在 T2 之前，或者 T2 在 T1 之前。
Okay, now the thing that we are trying to get to,
好的，现在我们要做的是，
the harder part is an equivalent schedule.
更难的部分是一个等效调度。
So here was a schedule that we saw that was correct,
所以这是我们看到的一个正确的调度，
it is not serial,
它不是串行的，
but as you'll see, this is correct
但如你所见，这是正确的，
and we want to look at this schedule
我们想看看这个调度，
and say the one on the left is equivalent to the serial schedule on the right,
并说左边的那个等同于右边的串行调度，
we want to be able to show that happens
我们希望能够证明这一点，
and in which case,
在这种情况下，
we'll say that schedule is safe and that's allowed.
我们说调度是安全的，这是允许的。
So the notion of equivalent schedule says,
所以，等效调度的概念是说，
allow some interleaving,
允许一些交错，
and as long as you can prove that the interleaving is safe,
只要你能证明交错是安全的，
and the proof of safety is going to be by saying
而安全的证据是，
all these actions are equivalent to some serial schedule,
所有这些操作都等效于某个串行调度，
in this case, one of those two,
在这种情况下，其中一个，
T1 followed by T2, or T2 followed by T1,
T1 在 T2 之前，或者 T2 在 T1 之前，
you are okay,
都是可以的，
you will end up with the correct answer.
你最终可以得到正确的答案。
So it sounds like magic,
这听起来像是魔术，
but there's a very simple way to go figure that out.
但有一个非常简单的方法来解决这个问题。
And this is the part that you were asking about,
这就是你所问的部分，
is like, okay, but why are the two correct states of the database,
就是，好的，但是为什么数据库的两种状态是正确的，
and that's really what we are relaxing a little bit in this notion of serializable,
这就是我们在这个可串行化中放松的一点，
and as I said,
正如我所说的，
there's a two sort of strict serializable,
有两种严格的串行化，
where that real world effect is taken into place,
在那里，现实世界的效果发生了，
it's stricter,
它更严格了，
but for the purpose of this class,
但是为了这门课的目的，
we're going to work with this notion,
我们将使用这个概念，
that we just have to prove it equivalent to one of the many equivalent serial schedules.
我们只需要证明它等效于许多串行调度之一。
And if you have two transactions,
如果你有两个事务，
there only two possible outcomes,
那么只有两种可能的结果，
if there were three, T1, T2, T3,
如果有三个， T1, T2, T3 ，
it could be,
它可能是，
first transaction could be either one of those,
第一个事务可能是其中之一，
there are three possible combinations,
有三种可能的组合，
then two, then one, right,
然后是两种，然后是一种，
so you you get that factorial effect.
所以你得到了阶乘效应。
We're going to think about these reads writes
我们将考虑这些读写，
in terms of conflicting actions, that can happen between these objects,
从可以发生在这些对象之间的冲突操作的角度，
like the As and the Bs and the Cs.
比如 A B 和 C 。
So we are going to have,
所以我们将会有，
we call these things anomalies,
我们称这些东西为异常，
and there are three different types,
有三种不同的类型，
a read could interfere,
读操作可能会干扰，
with a transaction, reads an object and something else writes to it,
在一个事务中，读取对象，其他人向其写入内容，
or a transaction writes an object and someone else reads that object,
或者，一个事务写入一个对象，其他人读取该对象，
the third one is two transaction,
第三种是两个事务，
transaction one writes to an object and the other transaction also writes to that object.
一个事务写入对象，另一个事务也写入该对象。
What is missing from this combination is read, read,
这种组合中缺少的是读读，
which is obviously not a conflict,
这显然不是冲突，
if I'm just reading this two transactions,
如果我只是在读这两个事务，
if I've just got a copy that's read only,
如果我只有一份只读的副本，
many transactions could read it,
那么许多事务都能读到它，
you're not going to conflict with each other,
你们不会互相冲突的，
it's, it's a read only copy.
这是只读副本。
Alright, so let's take these read-write conflicts and go look at that.
好的，让我们来看看这些读写冲突。
Here is a schedule,
这是一个调度，
in which there is a read of an object A,
有一个读取对象 A ，
followed by a write of an object A,
随后是写入对象 A ，
as these actions got interleaved,
这些操作相互交错，
and so that would be an example of a read write conflict.
这就是读写冲突的一个例子。
There are other conflicts in the schedule, too,
调度中还存在其他冲突，
but, but what's the downside of this read-write object conflict,
但是，这个读写对象冲突事务的缺点是什么，
transaction one read the value A,
事务一读取 A 的值，
T2 run,
T2 运行，
and then T1 reads that value and got a different value,
然后 T1 读取该值，并得到一个不同的值，
So it was 10 before,
所以它之前是 10 ，
T2 made it 19,
T2 把它改为 19 ，
T1 reads it again.
T1 再次读取它。
And obviously it has not seen the isolation principle,
显然，它没有看到隔离性原则，
in the same transaction,
在同一个事务中，
if I read the value twice,
如果我读取值两次，
I should see the same value
我应该看到相同的值，
unless someone else interfered with me.
除非其他人干扰我。
So it violates the isolation principle.
所以，它违反了隔离性原则。
And so this is that.
就是这样。
Alright, let's a look at the,
好的，我们来看一下，
and so that's called unrepeatable read,
这被称为不可重复读，
because when you have a read-write conflict,
因为当你有读写冲突时，
same transaction reads the value twice,
同一事务读取该值两次，
it's going to see different values.
它将看到不同的值。
A dirty read is,
脏读是指，
I read a value, let's say this 10,
我读了一个值，假设这个 10 ，
write it to be 12,
将其写为 12 ，
someone else reads the value, which is 12,
其他人读取值，即 12 ，
so far, no problem,
到目前为止，没有问题，
but what happens a little bit later is that,
但稍晚发生的是，
transaction T1 aborts
事务 T1 中止，
and when transaction T1 aborts,
当事务 T1 中止，
that value 12 should never have been read,
值 12 永远不应该被读取，
because it didn't get committed to the database,
因为它没有提交到数据库，
it was an intermediate value, which is getting thrown away, right,
这是一个被丢弃的中间值，
that's what abort should do.
这就是中止应该做的事情。
And so now transaction T2,
所以现在事务 T2 ，
when it was reading the value A,
当它读取值 A 时，
read a dirty value,
读取了一个脏值，
which should have never been in the database,
不应该存在于数据库中，
because of that abort.
因为那个中止。
So that's called a dirty read.
所以这就是所谓的脏读。
A write-write conflict is,
写写冲突是，
T1 is writing a value,
T1 写入一个值，
T2 is also writing that value
T2 也在写入那个值，
and when T1 writes another value B,
当 T1 写入另一个值 B ，
T1 it feels like it's writing 10 dollars,
T1 感觉就像写入了 10 美元，
imagine A and B are now columns
想象 A 和 B 现在是列，
and it's updating a record where dollar 10 is in Alice's account,
它更新 Alice 帐户中 10 美元的记录，
and it's column one is 10, the account, yeah, amount,
它的第一列是 10 ，账户金额，
and B is the name of the person,
而 B 是人名，
it thinks it's adding 10 to Alice,
它认为它给 Alice 增加了 10 ，
but the other conflict over there is
但这里的另一个冲突是，
writing to that same record, 19 and Bob.
写入相同的记录，19 和 Bob 。
So you have 10 in there,
所以这里你有 10 ，
19 and Bob got written to that same record,
19 和 Bob 也被写进了同一个记录，
and then you have this Alice, B that is written,
然后你就有了这个 Alice B 被写入，
that update of 19 and Bob just got overwritten.
19 和 Bob 的更新刚刚被覆盖。
So transaction two did its work,
所以，事务二完成了它的工作，
but its values just got overwritten,
但它的值刚刚被覆盖，
so it lost its update,
所以它丢失了更新，
it never got made, it made it to the database.
它从未没有进入数据库。
Okay?
好的？
So we use these properties to then define,
所以，我们使用这些属性来定义，
how to go make this equivalent schedule work.
如何使这个等效调度工作。
The two types of serializability, conflict serializability,
这两种类型的冲突可串行化，
which we'll talk about next,
这是我们接下来要讨论的，
something called View serializability,
有时称为视图可串行化，
since we are running out of time,
由于我们的时间不多了，
I might just totally go skip that piece,
我可能会完全跳过这一部分，
but I'll briefly allude to what that does.
但我会简要地暗示一下它的作用。
Okay, won't grill you with exam questions on view serializability, okay,
好的，我不会拿视图可视化的考试试题来盘问你，
so it's okay, if you don't totally get that,
所以如果你不完全理解，也没有关系，
conflict serializabilities was database systems implement
冲突可串行化是数据库系统实现的，
and let's just jump into that.
让我们直接跳到这个上面。
Let me just go with this graph form here
让我在这里使用这个图表形式，
to make it even more easier to understand.
以使它更容易理解。
So what we'll do is the following.
所以我们要做的是以下几点。
We take operations that we have,
我们采取我们已有的操作，
and here is the schedule that we have,
这是我们有的调度，
we will start going through that
我们将开始经历这一过程，
and enumerate all possible conflicts,
并列举所有可能的冲突，
read-write, write-write and write-read,
读写，写写，写读，
okay, those three conflicts.
好的，这三种冲突。
We create a graph called the dependence graph,
我们创建一个称为依赖图的图，
so I've got two nodes in that graph, T1 and T2,
所以我在图中有两个节点， T1 和 T2 ，
every time a transaction comes in, a new node will be added,
每次有事务进入时，都会添加新的节点，
so the graph will have as many transactions,
所以，该图将具有尽可能多的事务，
that are active in the system at any point in time.
在任何时间点系统中处于活动状态的（事务）。
Now I'll just start going through the schedule
现在我将开始遍历调度，
and start marking all the conflicts,
并开始标记所有的冲突，
and I start with the first conflict that I see,
我从我看到的第一个冲突开始，
which is a read-write,
这是一个读写，
doesn't matter what the conflict is,
是什么冲突并不重要，
as soon as I have one of those three types of conflict,
一旦我有了这三种冲突中的一种，
read-write, write-write or write-read,
读写，写写或写读，
I'm going to put an arrow there,
我就会在那里放一个箭头，
so the first conflict A is on this object A
所以第一个冲突在这个对象 A 上，
and it goes from T1 to T2,
它从 T1 到 T2 ，
because T1 happens before T2 in the schedule, right,
因为在调度中 T1 在 T2 之前，
so I'll draw a directed arc from T1 to T2.
所以我会画一条从 T1 到 T2 的有向弧线。
Does that make sense?
这能理解吗？
So, really simple,
所以，真的很简单，
I'm going to just walk through this,
我将遍历这个，
for every conflict that I have,
对所遇到的每一个冲突，
I'll draw a directed graph in the order in which this conflict is happening.
按照冲突发生的顺序绘制一个有向图。
Now I go and find the next conflict,
现在我要去寻找下一个冲突，
which is this write followed by read,
它是写后面跟着读，
and I will do that.
我会这样做。
So the proof is really simple,
所以，证明非常简单，
you take a schedule,
你拿到一个调度，
if you walk through it
如果你遍历它，
and draw a line for every read-write, write-write or write-read conflict,
为每一个读写、写写或写读冲突画一条线，
and if it, there's a cycle in that graph,
如果这张图里有一个环，
you have a bad schedule,
你的调度是糟糕的，
that schedule will violate the isolation principle,
这个调度将会违反隔离性原则，
that schedule should never have been allowed to run in the database system.
这个调度永远不应该被允许在数据库系统中运行。
In the next class,
在下一节课中，
we'll see mechanisms that you can use to prevent that from ever happening.
我们将看到可以用来防止这种情况发生的机制。
Does that make sense,
这能理解吗，
if you didn't get anything else because of that bug in the slide,
如果你因为幻灯片中的那个错误而没有得到任何其他东西，
that's the main thing I want you to get from this isolation principle.
这就是我希望你从这个隔离性原则中得到的主要东西。
What direction?
方向是什么？
The edges go in the time order,
这些边是按时间顺序排列的，
see, so look at the write followed by read,
请看写入后面跟着读取，
the red line that is shown here right now,
现在这里显示的红线，
it's going from T1 to T2, right,
它是从 T1 到 T2 ，
the read, the write in A happened before the read in T2,
对 A 的写入发生在 T2 读取之前，
so I will draw a directed line from T1 to T2,
所以我将从 T1 到 T2 画一条有向线，
saying some action in T1 happens before the action in T2,
表示在 T1 中的一些动作发生在 T2 中的动作之前，
which means T2 better not do stuff,
这意味着 T2 最好不要做事情，
that is the other way around,
这是相反的，
because now I've got a contradictory state,
因为现在我有一个矛盾的状态，
that I'm going to end up with.
我将以此结束。
Okay?
好的？
So the serial schedule is, the schedule is the,
所以，串行调度是，调度是，
the time on the left side is
左侧的时间是，
the order in which a database is seeing those actions.
数据库看到这些操作的顺序。
And let's come to construct this graph,
让我们来构建这张图，
and what we'll see in the next class is,
我们将在下一节课中看到的是，
the [] is starts to say,
开始说的是，
the second stuff which is going to cause this graph to complete,
第二件事将导致这个图完成，
it will stop,
它会停下来，
it won't let,
它不会让，
it will basically not let this thing proceed,
它不会让这件事执行，
beyond the write of B,
下面的对 B 的写入，
because it says, if I allow this write to happen,
因为它说，如果我允许这个写入发生，
this arc to form,
这条弧线形成，
I will have a conflict,
我就会有冲突，
so this line,
这一行，
it will pause that,
它将暂停它，
it will stop transaction T1 from proceeding
它将停止事务 T1 继续执行，
with the techniques we'll talk about in the next class.
使用我们将在下一节课中讨论的技术。
Yep.
是的。
Does it need to what?
它需要什么？
Yeah, and then it may need to abort something or delay something,
是的，然后它可能需要放弃一些东西或推迟一些东西，
so we'll, we'll talk about that, right,
所以我们会讨论这个，
so there are sometimes where it may just say,
所以有时它可能只会说，
you know what, I need to abort
你知道吗，我需要放弃，
and I can't go any further.
我不能再继续了。
Alright, so it's really that simple.
好的，就是这么简单。
We will construct this graph and
我们将构建这个图，
now we have this beautiful proof that says,
现在我们有了这个漂亮的证明，它说，
how do I have correct isolation property.
我如何才能拥有正确的隔离性。
All right, so here is three transactions,
好的，这是三个事务，
just to show this in a slightly more complicated way.
只是想用一种稍微复杂一点的方式来说明这一点。
As I walk down,
当我走下去的时候，
the first conflict is that read to write,
第一个冲突就是读写，
there are other conflicts in there,
这里面还有其他的冲突，
there's a W(A) at T1 to read an A,
这里有 T1 的 W(A) 到读取 A ，
I'm not showing every possible conflict in there,
我没有展示所有可能的冲突，
but both of them induce arc from T1 to T2,
但是它们都会引出从 T1 到 T2 的弧线，
it's just a hazard,
这只是一种[危险]，
and then there are other conflicts,
然后还有其他的冲突，
but that will just redo that same line,
但这只会重做同样的线，
you don't have to redraw that line multiple times,
你不必多次重新画这条线，
one arc is, one arc is enough, right.
一条弧线就够了。
That's all this is showing,
这就是这一切所显示的，
as you go further down,
当你继续往下走，
we see another conflict from T2 to T1,
我们看到另一个从 T2 到 T1 的冲突，
and that's all there is in here.
这就是这里所有的东西。
So this basically says,
所以这基本上是在说，
in this schedule,
在这个调度中，
even though there's a bunch of interleaving going on between the three transactions,
尽管这三个事务之间存在大量交错，
this you can prove to be correct.
你可以证明这个是正确的。
And can you guess what's the correct serial schedule,
你可以猜猜正确的串行调度是什么，
look at the graph.
看这张图。
Yeah, it's going to be the order of that graph,
使得，这将是图的顺序，
T2, it's like T2 happened first,
比如 T2 最先发生，
then T1 happened,
然后 T1 发生，
then T3 happened,
然后 T3 发生，
whoops, it's as if that was the serial order in which they were executed
这就像这是它们被执行的顺序，
and we were just running one transaction at a time.
而我们一次只运行一个事务。
And that's the whole idea,
这就是整个想法，
now, if you get why this graph makes sense,
现在，如果你明白为什么这张图是有意义的，
it's trivial,
它是微不足道的，
but it took a little while for people to figure this out,
但人们花了一小段时间才弄明白这一点，
it wasn't that trivial,
它并不是那么微不足道，
and that's what many of these beautiful ideas are,
这就是这些美丽的想法中的许多，
they seem simple only in retrospect.
回想起来，它们看起来很简单。
So, forget everything I said with that bug in the slide,
所以，忘记我在幻灯片中对那个错误所说的一切，
this, if you get it,
如果你明白了，
you understand how isolation works.
你就会明白隔离性是如何工作的。
Yeah, and we'll talk about aborts and other kinds of special handling in there,
是的，我们将在那里讨论中止和其他类型的特殊处理，
but what is true is that,
但事实是，
even before the abort,
即使在中止之前，
if you start to see a cycle,
如果你开始看到环，
you know you will end up in a bad situation,
你知道你会陷入糟糕的境地，
so you need to stop it.
所以你需要阻止它。
Because time is evolving,
因为时间在发展，
I as the database transaction manager,
我作为数据库事务管理者，
if I'm at this point in time
如果我在这个时间点上，
and I've been told,
并且我被告知，
should I admit this read of B,
我是否应该接受 B 的这个读取，
I have to make a decision,
我必须做出决定，
if I'm this pessimistic transaction management system,
如果我是个悲观的事务管理系统，
pessimistic isolation management,
悲观的隔离性管理，
if I I will have to decide whether to let that happen or not,
我将不得不决定是否让这种情况发生，
if I'm optimistic, I'll let it go,
如果我是乐观的，我会让它继续，
and in the end I will figure out, right,
最终，我会弄明白，
so that's the difference between the pessimistic and the optimistic.
这就是悲观和乐观的区别。
It has been created while it's happening, right,
它在发生的时候被创造出来，
so you can imagine something like this is happening in the system,
所以你可以想象这样的事情正在系统中发生，
[] step is run,
[]步运行，
we start with begin on T1,
我们从 T1 开始，
then read of A is done, write of A is done,
然后读取 A 完成，写入 A 完成，
system says I can let you go,
系统说我可以让你继续，
then when the write of A comes,
然后，当写入 A 到来，
system is say, you know what, I need to put an arc in this graph,
系统会说，你知道吗，我需要在这个图表中画一条弧线，
so as time is progressing,
所以，随着时间的推移，
these arcs are being done,
这些弧线正在被完成，
the reads and writes are being presented to the system that evolves.
读写被呈现给发展的系统。
And that's the difference between the pessimistic method and the optimistic,
这就是悲观的方法和乐观的区别，
pessimistic will say,
悲观的会说，
first time I think there's a problem, I'm going to stop you,
当我第一次认为有问题时，我会阻止你，
and we'll see how in the next class,
我们将在下一节课上看到，
and optimistic is I let everything go,
乐观的是，我让一切都过去，
but I know how to get you back to a safe place,
但我知道如何把你带回一个安全的地方，
if bad things had happened.
如果发生了糟糕的事情。
This is not optimistic,
这不是乐观的，
it's just saying,
它只是在说，
how do I detect that something is good or bad,
我如何才能检测到某件事是好的还是坏的，
but this is the mechanism.
但这就是机制。
Yep.
是的。
If it is a cycle, it is not okay,
如果是环的话，就不行了，
how do I find the cycle,
我怎么找到环，
when do I find the cycle is where the difference is,
我什么时候找到环是不同之处，
do I find the cycle as soon as it is formed,
我是不是在环形成就尽快找到它，
or do I find the cycle after I let everything go.
或者，在我让在一切继续之后找到环。
So that's basically the whole theory of saying,
所以，整个理论基本上就是说，
is this equivalent to that order or not.
这是否等同于那个顺序。
So here is another example,
这是另一个例子，
and this is where we are getting into this new serializability
这就是我们进入这种新的串行化，
and kind of what is happening over here in,
这里正在发生的事情，
here what's happening is,
这里正在发生的事情是，
A is getting 10 dollars removed from it
A 拿出 10 美元，
and there's a sum that is being calculated that's getting printed out over here,
有一个正在计算中的 sum 在这里打印出来，
of course, there are problems with this transaction,
当然，这个事务也有问题，
because that one causes the arc from T1 to T2,
因为这导致从 T1 到 T2 的弧线，
and then you have this transaction,
然后你有这个事务，
so this is not serializable,
所以这是不可串行化的，
but if instead of,
但如果不是，
the second transactions doing a sum of the two transactions,
第二个事务做两个事务的 sum ，
if the code in there was only about saying,
如果其中的代码只是，
find the number of transactions that have values account values greater than 100,
查找值帐户值大于 100 的事务的数量，
the fact that it is a cycle,
这是一个环的事实并不重要，
doesn't matter from the semantics of that second transaction,
从第二个事务的语义来看，
at a very high level,
在一个高级别的层次上，
that's what view serializability is it.
这就是视图可串行化的含义。
If you knew something about the semantics of what was happening,
如果你对正在发生的事情的语义有所了解，
you will admit a few more types of schedules that you would not otherwise.
你将会承认更多类型的调度，否则你将不会这样做。
And as I said,
正如我所说的，
that's all I wanted to know for this class,
这就是我想知道的这节课的全部内容，
if you didn't get that, that's okay.
如果你不明白，那也没关系。
Let it go,
随它去吧，
we're not going to talk too much about view serializability,
我们不会过多地谈论视图的可串行化，
it will just allow certain types of cycles,
它只是允许某些类型的环，
because it says I think the application is okay.
因为它说我认为应用程序是好的。
All right.
好的。
And there's a formal definition of it,
这里有一个对它的正式的定义，
if you're interested in looking at it in terms of what it allows,
如果你有兴趣从它允许的方面来看它，
it basically allows a few more schedules than a strictly serial schedule will allow.
它基本上允许比严格的串行调度允许的多的调度。
Alright, so conflict serializability is the main thing that we want you to know about.
好的，所以冲突可串行化是我们想让你知道的主要事情。
Alright, pictorially,
好的，图画形式，
here's the universe of all possible schedules,
以下是所有可能的调度，
including the bad ones,
包括糟糕的调度，
the ones we don't want to happen.
那些我们不希望发生的。
Sorry, yeah, serial schedule is that strict serial stuff which you talked about,
抱歉，是的，串行调度是严格串行内容，
T1 followed by T2,
T1 在 T2 之前，
and that's the only thing that allow conflict serializable is,
这是唯一允许冲突可串行化的事情，
if we are allowing a few more combinations
如果我们允许更多的组合，
and view serializable is where you might have a little bit more by way of this application performance.
而视图可串行化是通过应用程序性能可能会有更多的东西。
And there are many more layers in there,
这里还有更多的层次，
and we'll uncover some of those in later classes
我们将在后面的课程中发现其中的一些，
and again, a lot more in the detail class.
在细节课中也会有更多的内容。
So we still have one more letter to cover,
所以我们还有一个字母要讲，
which is the D, which is the durability,
那就是 D ，也就是持久性，
right, we did atomicity, consistency, isolation,
我们说了原子性、一致性、隔离性，
which is where we spend most of the time today,
这是我们今天花的大部分时间，
and the last one is durability,
最后一个是持久性，
which will cover really fast.
这将会讲得非常快。
Durability, we have a full lecture coming on it,
持久性，我们会有一个完整的课程讲它，
on this in the second class now,
在从现在的第二节课上，
which is about making sure that the changes that we make to the system,
关于确保我们对系统所做的更改，
we're making changes to A, the Bs and the Cs and stuff like that,
我们对 A B 和 C 之类的内容进行更改，
just in memory,
只是在内存中，
if you're updating a column value or a record,
如果你更新列值或记录，
that's sitting in the buffer pool,
它位于缓冲池中，
but what happens if you have a power loss
但是如果你断电了，
and memory is volatile,
内存是不稳定的，
so those changes never made it to disk,
这些更改从未到磁盘，
but you might have committed that transaction.
但你可能已经提交了该事务。
So durability is the aspect that says,
所以持久性是指，
if the database commits the transaction,
如果数据库提交了事务，
oh, by the way, the database is allowed to use a buffer pool,
顺便说一句，允许数据库使用缓冲池，
because that's an efficient way to build data processing systems,
因为这是一种有效的方式来构建数据处理系统，
you don't want to go to disk every time
你不会希望每次访问磁盘，
you want a buffer pool,
你想要缓冲池，
because buffer pool, accessing data in buffer pool is just so much faster than accessing things on disk.
因为访问缓冲池中的数据比访问磁盘上的数据要快得多。
But if the database is, it's committed,
但是如果数据库已经提交，
you want to make sure that,
你需要确保，
if there's power failure,
如果出现电源故障，
you can get the right values in the database.
你可以在数据库中获得正确的值。
So durability will do that,
所以，持久性会做这个，
by making sure when the commit happens,
通过确保提交发生时，
it's going to make sure certain things get written to disk
它将确保将某些内容写入磁盘，
and it'll try to do very small amounts of [] write to disk,
它将尝试对磁盘执行非常少的[]写入，
so that it can provide this durability property.
以便提供这种持久性属性。
And as I said,
正如我说的，
in two lectures from now, we'll talk about that.
在之后的两节课中，我们将讨论这个。
So that's basically what ACID looks like.
所以，这基本上就是 ACID 看起来的样子。
Yeah, we can talk about that offline,
是的，我们可以在线下讨论这个，
the answer is the principles will probably apply,
答案是，可能会应用的原则，
is like I have volatile storage and non volatile storage
就像我有易失性存储和非易失性存储，
and I can apply this principle of durability across any of those systems.
我可以将这个持久性原则应用于其中任何一个系统。
Yeah, yeah, the same principles to apply.
是的，同样的原则也适用。
Yep.
是的。
The logs, sorry.
日志，抱歉。
Yeah, the logs will be kept in memory,
是的，日志将保存在内存中，
we'll get to that in two lectures from now,
从现在开始，我们将在两节课中讲到这个，
the log records that we create will be kept in memory too,
我们创建的日志记录也将保存在内存中，
but at appropriate times,
但在适当的时候，
we will actually flush them out to disk
我们会将它们刷新到磁盘上，
to guarantee the durability property.
以保证持久性。
We'll talk about that,
我们将会谈过这个问题，
what happens if the log fails,
如果日志失败，会发生什么情况，
that's the whole lecture, two lectures from now.
这就是从现在开始的两节课。
It's a full lecture,
这是一节完整的课，
I can give you a ten second answer,
我可以给你十秒钟的回答，
the ten second answer is,
十秒钟的答案是，
that we will make sure that absolutely what must be written to disk is written,
我们将确保绝对必须写入磁盘的内容被写入，
and if we write the wrong thing,
如果我们写错了东西，
we will look at the value and undo if we need to,
我们会查看它的值，然后如果我们需要的话，撤销它。
we'll do one of two things with stuff we write on disk,
我们将用我们写在磁盘上的东西做两件事中的一件，
either redo the operation, because it's inconsistent with what was in memory
要么重做操作，因为它与内存中的内容不一致，
or undo it, because we wrote something that we should not have written.
要么撤销它，因为我们写了不应该写的东西。
So we'll do redo and undo logic on on those.
所以，我们将对它们进行重做和撤消逻辑。
Okay, so here's the conclusions.
好的，这是总结。
Concurrency control and recovery amongst the most important functions that transactions,
并发控制和恢复是事务最重要的功能之一，
are super important,
是非常重要的，
but that's a putit, definitional component of database systems,
但这是数据库系统的一个陈旧的、定义的组件，
and if you go back to the early days of database systems,
如果你回到数据库系统的早期，
that's why they started getting adopted in enterprises,
这就是为什么它们开始在企业中被采用，
because they allowed all this record keeping.
因为它们允许所有这些记录保存。
I need five minutes to go over a couple of things,
我需要五分钟来回顾一些事情，
but before that, we've talked about this a few times,
但在此之前，我们已经谈过几次了，
that there are, there's still a lot more things you can do with transactions,
对于事务，你还可以做更多的事情，
there's this breakthrough paper that came out from Google called Spanner,
Google 发布了一篇突破性的论文，名为 Spanner ，
by the way, before that, they were doing eventual consistency stuff in many parts,
顺便说一句，在此之前，他们在许多部分都在做最终一致性工作，
and they realized, wow, application programmers can't quite do that,
他们意识到，哇，应用程序程序员不能完全做到这一点，
so they actually build a very hard thing,
所以他们实际上构建了一个非常难的东西，
which is a globally distributed system that can do transactions,
它是一个全球分布式系统，可以做事务，
where the transactions could be touching objects in the database, which is distributed,
事务可以是访问分布式数据库中的对象，
so it might touch an object in London, touch an object in the US
所以它可以访问伦敦的对象，访问美国的对象，
and commit that transaction across the globe as one transaction
并将该事务作为一个事务提交到全球各地，
and do that fast and efficiently.
并快速高效地完成这一操作。
And the reason they did that is,
他们这样做的原因是，
if they kept the eventual consistency stuff,
如果他们保持最终一致性，
all kinds of application programmer bugs was showing unp,
各种应用程序编程错误就会出现，
like the AD system would report wrong things,
比如广告系统会报告错误的东西，
it would tell the same advertiser, Proctor and Gamble, for example, in London,
它会告诉同一个广告商，例如，在伦敦的宝洁公司，
this is how many impressions we showed,
这就是我们展示的印象，
and the same campaign in US would show a different number
而在美国同样的活动会显示一个不同的数字，
and these two guys get on the phone and say,
这两个人拿起电话说，
what the heck is happening,
到底发生了什么，
what impressions did we really show,
我们到底展示了什么印象，
you want that answer to be precise,
你想要准确的答案，
because someone's paying money for it,
因为有人为它付钱，
that was one of the big reasons why they went and built that.
这是他们去构建这个的主要原因之一。
It's a beautiful system,
这是一个美丽的系统，
requires atomic clocks,
需要原子钟，
where you need satellite syncing across the data centers,
你需要在数据中心之间进行卫星同步，
so that the two clocks are not out of sync.
这样两个时钟才不会不同步，
CockroachDB was formed by people from Google who worked on this
CockroachDB 是由 Google 的工作人员创建的，
and have a version of it that doesn't require satellite clocks,
他们有一个不需要卫星时钟的版本，
but fascinating feel,
但令人着迷的是，
there's still a lot of new things that are happening.
仍然有很多新事物正在发生。
Bonus round, I leave this link in the slides if you want to.
奖励环节，我在幻灯片中留下这个链接，如果你想要。
We've talked about all kinds of different models and levels of consistency,
我们已经讨论了各种不同的模型和一致性级别，
but there's a lot more,
但还有更多，
and you can play around with that chart.
你可以玩弄那张图表。
But I want to spend a couple minutes on the project #3,
但我想在项目 #3 上花几分钟时间，
which is on query execution.
它是关于查询执行的。
And the overview of this project is,
这个项目的概况是，
we essentially have,
我们基本上有，
these are the different components of Bustub,
这些都是 Bustub 的不同组成部分，
as you've gotten to know and love over time,
随着时间的推移你逐渐了解和热爱，
project #3 is related to the optimizer and the query execution
项目 #3 与优化器和查询执行有关，
and project #4 that's coming will be query execution in the transaction management piece.
而即将到来的项目 #4 将是事务管理部分中的查询执行。
Okay, so what is project #3,
好的，那么项目 #3 是什么，
you're going to add access methods,
你将添加访问方法，
two different access methods,
两种不同的访问方法，
sequential scan and index scan,
顺序扫描和索引扫描，
you will also do insert, delete and updates,
你还将做插入、删除和更新，
so these are the operators stuff that you're going to add,
这些是你要添加的运算符，
you're going to add these as new operators that are in the system,
你将把它们添加为系统中的新运算符，
two different types of Join, nested loops Join and hash Join
两种不同类型的 Join ，嵌套循环 Join 和哈希 Join ，
and there's some miscellaneous window aggregation function, Limit Sort and Top-k.
还有一些其他的窗口聚合函数， Limit Sort 和 Top-k 。
You'll also touch the optimizer,
你还将接触到优化器，
so there's already an optimizer in Bustub
所以 Bustub 中已经有了一个优化器，
and to convert a query,
用来转换查询，
if a query has both an ORDER BY and a LIMIT,
如果查询同时具有 ORDER BY 和 LIMIT ，
you can convert it to a with a simple transformation into a Top-k query.
你可以通过简单的转换，转换为 Top-k 查询。
So that will give you a chance to look at how do optimizers work.
所以，这将给你一个机会来查看优化器是如何工作的。
If you see a nested loops,
如果你看到嵌套的循环，
that's often a bad idea,
这通常不是一个好主意，
so in the optimizer,
所以，在优化器中，
you will write a rule to convert nested loops to hash Join,
你将编写一个规则，将嵌套循环转换为哈希 Join ，
because those are typically much faster.
因为这通常要快得多。
And similarly with sequential scan to index scan,
同样，顺序扫描到索引扫描，
if an index exists, don't do a sequential scan,
如果存在索引，请不要执行顺序扫描，
go use an index scan.
而是使用索引扫描。
These is,
这些就是，
think of it as the heuristic stuff,
把它想象成启发式的东西，
that we talked about in the optimization stuff, right,
我们在优化的东西里谈到的，
not cost based heuristics, just rules based.
不是基于成本的启发式，而是基于规则的。
The leaderboard will require making deeper changes to the optimizer,
排行榜将需要对优化器进行更深层次的更改，
so even if you have awesome code from project #1 and project #2,
所以，即使你有来自项目 #1 和项目 #2 的令人惊叹的代码，
you're guaranteed not to get good high stats on the leaderboard,
你也肯定不会在排行榜上获得好的高的统计数据，
unless you go add new optimization rules
除非你添加新的优化规则，
and that's all described in the project,
这在项目中都有描述，
you'll be adding rules to window aggregation and and top-k.
你将向窗口聚合和 top-k 添加规则。
Quick tips, start with the easy stuff,
小贴士，从简单的事情开始，
the insert and sequential scan,
插入和顺序扫描，
that's the easiest stuff,
这是最简单的事情，
get it right,
先把它弄好，
before you go do other things with it.
在你用它做其他事情之前。
And the key thing is,
关键的事情是，
now you can actually go and run Bustub in, in the browser.
现在你可以真的在浏览器中运行 Bustub 了。
So I'm going to close this here.
所以我要在这里结束了。
And whoops, Powerpoint don't need that anymore.
然后，不再需要 Powerpoint 了。
And if you go look at Bustub now,
如果你现在去看 Bustub ，
you can actually go and run Bustub in the browser.
你实际上可以在浏览器中运行 Bustub 。
let me go find the link here.
让我找到这里的链接。
Yep.
是的。
[Chi], who's just an awesome programmer,
Chi ，他是一个很棒的程序员，
has written this version,
编写了这个版本，
which completely runs in VASM code in the browser
它完全在浏览器中以 VASM 代码运行，
and it's already loaded with some tables in there,
并且已经在其中加载了一些表，
and you can start to do things,
你可以开始做一些事情，
like SELECT * FROM _mock_table_,
比如 SELECT * FROM _mock_table_，
and do things like that,
然后做这样的事情，
whoops, where's my semicolon,
糟糕，我的分号在哪里，
and you can start to run stuff.
你就可以开始运行东西了。
You can use this to test if your code works,
你可以使用它来测试你的代码是否工作，
our solution is sitting behind that.
我们的解决方案就在这之后。
Yep.
是的。
Yeah, so the,
是的，所以，
use this as a reference,
将这个作为参考，
don't use great scope as a way of doing your debugging,
不要使用大范围作为进行调试的方法，
write your tests,
编写你的测试，
otherwise, you will not do well in this project.
否则，你在这个项目中不会做得很好。
So hopefully it's a fun project,
所以希望这是一个有趣的项目，
start with the simple stuff,
从简单的事情开始，
it may seem like a lot,
这可能看起来很多，
and you'll be surprised how quickly you start knocking things off.
你会惊讶于你开始快速完成事情。
Okay, all right, thank you, DJ, [] hit it.
好的，谢谢， DJ []，点击它。